<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Jeffrey Moro</title>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/"/>
 <updated>2017-02-18T12:24:50-05:00</updated>
 <id>http://localhost:4000</id>
 <author>
   <name>Jeffrey Moro</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>On Children and Water</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/02/17/on-children-and-water/"/>
   <updated>2017-02-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/02/17/on-children-and-water</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few interconnected thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the Grammy awards on Sunday, Beyoncé performed the song “Love Drought” from her album &lt;em&gt;LEMONADE&lt;/em&gt;. You know the song, you know the album, you know the performance, but let’s go ahead and watch it anyway, if only as a healing practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/A_Y5g-0kQx8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A week or so before this performance, Beyoncé announced on Instagram (with characteristic grandeur and withholding, a master of the modern art of the image) that she is pregnant with twins. It is an image that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.okayafrica.com/in-brief/beyonce-channeled-yoruba-goddess-oshun-maternity-photoshoot/&quot;&gt;as many have pointed out&lt;/a&gt;, deploys pointed references, mediated mostly through the element of water, to maternal deities in Yoruba spirituality. The official video for “Love Drought” does the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;2&quot;&gt;2.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twenty minutes before I wrote this post, the United States Senate &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/02/17/us/politics/scott-pruitt-environmental-protection-agency.html?smprod=nytcore-iphone&amp;amp;smid=nytcore-iphone-share&quot;&gt;confirmed Scott Pruitt as the head of the Environmental Protection Agency&lt;/a&gt;. He is most well-known for his deep ties to the petroleum industry and his frequent lawsuits, one of which he is the current plaintiff, against the E.P.A. with intent to destabilize and destroy it utterly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not a surprising move from the Trump Administration and the Republican Party more generally, who have dedicated themselves to weaponizing the idea of dramatic irony. Appointees like Scott Pruitt and Betsy DeVos (Secretary of Education, he types wanting to vomit on his keyboard) are ideologically opposed not only to the missions of the agencies that they run but of these agencies’ rights to exist in the first place. Such appointments are part of a broader right-wing tactic not only to shift capital from the poor to the rich, but also to rig the game in favor of their own ideological opposition to the idea of government: make the government so broken, so dysfunctional, so useless and shattered, and then step back and declare that government simply &lt;em&gt;cannot&lt;/em&gt; work, and free enterprise must step in to take up the reins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what I’m thinking about is water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;3&quot;&gt;3.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been more takes on the Women’s March that followed Trump’s inauguration than I care to read, and I spend most of my time getting Mad On The Internet. So I’m not offering a take beyond the idea that mass mobilization against the Republican Party, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.democracynow.org/2016/5/16/noam_chomsky_climate_change_nuclear_proliferation&quot;&gt;whom I regard alongside Noam Chomsky as a domestic terrorist organization&lt;/a&gt;, is in aggregate a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But one thing that gave me a tremendous amount of hope, and that I hope continues to stay at the core of any resistance or revolution to come, hashtagged or not, was the repeated attempts on the part of the March organizers to center indigenous voices, indigenous women’s voices, those people who are on the front lines of absolute central fights over neocolonialism, the right to sovereignty, the imbricated nature of ecological and racial justice, and so much more. The #NoDAPL cry that water is life seems to me to need to be a central organizing call across all registers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;4&quot;&gt;4.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growing up, my mother always said that she never imagined that she would have children. She didn’t see herself as the kind of person who would settle easily into motherhood. So as not to then make me think that I was unwanted (as well, not joking now, to communicate a shift in her thinking that I believe is completely genuine), she would tell me that that all changed when she actually &lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt; children. When they were hers, she said, she came to understand the fierce, complex love of a parent, of a mother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;5&quot;&gt;5.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, when I was an adult, and when the epistemological question of having children of my own, of then being the same age that my parents were when they started to consider seriously the question of having children, raised its head, I had a conversation with my father in which we talked about nuclear war. In the 80’s, he said, the common refrain was that there was no point in having children, how could one justify having children in such dark, horrifying times, when the prospect of annihilation was just around the corner? And yet (a conservative moral that nonetheless belies a deep ethics of love, and self-preservation, and desire, and fear, and still love), they did anyway, because that was what one did, not just out of ideology, but out of compassion and a desire to see things made right, to imagine a future for the species.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;6&quot;&gt;6.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not have any children. Like my mother, I do not consider myself the kind of person who has any business being a parent. Like my father, I have a hard time seeing a world in which any children of mine, or anyone’s children, can rely on clean water, clean air, clean soil. These needs are elemental, and we are undermining them. Or more properly, we are overmining them, taking too much from them and giving nothing in return. We are not stewarding. The United States of America currently runs on the principle of maximum extraction. These reasons are deeply ideological and arise from a complex web of settler colonialism, Evangelical and prosperty Christianity, and plain old capitalism. But I think about the agents at the center, even as I see them within a web of forces. I cannot pretend to understand what goes through these men’s minds at night, in the dark, when their children are asleep and they are trying to sleep. Perhaps they think (or they know) that they can buy clean water, clean air, clean soil. They can go outside the world they are making. &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/matter/all-dressed-up-for-mars-and-nowhere-to-go-7e76df527ca0#.hi5op3k8x&quot;&gt;Perhaps they will go to Mars.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;7&quot;&gt;7.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gone on the record at parties as saying that I think that the end of the world is very much upon us, or has in fact already happened. (I am not very fun at parties.) When I say this, I do not mean catastrophic apocalypse, although certainly the conditions could be right for that at any moment since the Trinity Test. I mean this on an ontological level: that certain actions occur in history that make the continuance of a certain set of assumptions about what the world is and how it works impossible. And that we are living through such a time. The world has ended many times over, and other worlds have emerged. This is not to say that one should accept the results of such a process, or imagine that the conditions of apocalypse under which we live are irrevocable or immutable. If the world is going to end then we should at least have some say in what that ending means and what a possible beginning can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suppose this is also why I think that a resistance or revolution that does not center indigenous women, Black women, refugees, those who know firsthand what it means to live through the end of a world and what conditions must be not to simply survive but to thrive, is useless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suppose this is also why I think a lot about children and water these days.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On Staying Up Late to Look at Arbitrary Borders</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/01/24/arbitrary-borders/"/>
   <updated>2017-01-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/01/24/arbitrary-borders</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I can’t sleep (which is most nights these days) I tend to do a few things:&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Put on David Attenborough nature documentaries, Norwegian slow TV, or Max Richter’s &lt;em&gt;SLEEP&lt;/em&gt; album, sometimes all at once&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Play &lt;em&gt;Dragon Quest&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trawl Google Earth for the weirdest and farthest-flung things I can find on this planet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s talk about this last one, particularly how it lets me excavate a recent obsession of mine: the United States / Canada border.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like I imagine many of you, I’ve been obsessed with maps from a young age. Road maps in the car, atlases in the library, Narnia and Middle Earth sketched in the first or last pages of a book. I grew up in suburbia so there wasn’t much in the way of adventure except into other people’s backyards: maps were useful ways of extending a sense of adventure into the precisely the sphere I was most comfortable with, i.e. never leaving the library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I go through phases with regards to what I’m interested in and looking for on Google Earth. For a while I looked for Pacific Islands, driven by a sense of 1) living in a relatively cold place and 2) seeing places that I was almost certainly never going to get to see in real life. When I was preparing to move from New England to D.C., I spent a lot of time in the countryside of Maryland, Virginia, and Pennsylvania, interested in spaces that were close enough to drive to but that felt separated and far-flung. I spent some time looking up the most remote parts of each state—Idaho wins by a long-shot—amazed at the human capacity to proliferate, spread, and dominate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I spent some time looking at the Canadian border. It’s pretty weird! I guess all political borders are, in the end, even those ostensibly bounded by something “real,” like rivers or mountains. They’re all relatively arbitrary, imagined spaces, where humans draw a line and the bears don’t notice or care. Unless we build a wall. The bears will have a hard time then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of my favorite parts of the Canadian border:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-point-roberts-washington&quot;&gt;1. Point Roberts, Washington&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/borders-1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/@48.9742619,-123.0557913,11z/data=!3m1!1e3&quot;&gt;Point Roberts, Washington&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The U.S./Canada border follows the 45th parallel above New England (set after the American Revolutionary War by the Treaty of Paris) and the 49th parallel above the Midwest and Western United States (set by the Treaty of Oregon in 1846, during the period of western expansion). Given that these parallels are just latitude lines, they don’t correspond to anything geographically “real” or physical. So you end up with places like Point Roberts: tiny spits of land that happen to pass under the 49th parallel and thus belong to the U.S., even though they’re only connected (by land at least) to Canada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-the-northwest-angle-minnesota&quot;&gt;2. The Northwest Angle, Minnesota&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/borders-2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/@49.1780168,-95.0571341,10z/data=!3m1!1e3&quot;&gt;The Northwest Angle, Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly to Point Roberts, the Northwest Angle is another patch of land that’s technically in the United States, but you can only get to it from Canada. (It also takes the record for northern-most point in the contiguous United States.) Why does it exist? Wikipedia claims it’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Northwest_Angle&quot;&gt;map-making error&lt;/a&gt;, formed during the negotiation of the Treaty of Paris because no one expected that the Mississippi River wouldn’t run far north enough to constitute a border intersection with the Lake of the Woods. The north-south line they picked, when extended, happens to cut off this small patch of land. It seems like it’s mostly moose, which is fitting, I think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-estcourt-maine--pohénégamook-québec&quot;&gt;3. Estcourt, Maine / Pohénégamook, Québec&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/borders-3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/@47.4571237,-69.2274827,18z/data=!3m1!1e3&quot;&gt;Estcourt, Maine / Pohénégamook, Québec&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, that’s a border line running through peoples’ backyards, and no, it’s not just a Google Maps error. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.atlasobscura.com/articles/the-incredible-complications-of-living-atop-the-us-canada-border&quot;&gt;Atlas Obscura has a great article&lt;/a&gt; on the weirdness that is Estcourt, Maine and its sister town of Pohénégamook, Québec, which more or less form one complete town that straddles the border. One of the more surreal observations from the article is that if your backyard crosses the border from Canada into the U.S., you can still be in it, but if you cross over your own fence—your own border fence, as it were—you’re illegally trespassing. Locals say that the border was more or less permeable for a long time, given that it’s arbitrary and costly to enforce, but then after September 11th, 2001, security ramped up, making life considerably more difficult for those who accidentally cross it—whether to talk to a neighbor or get a ball thrown over the fence by mistake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;There once was a time where this list was just “read and drink herbal tea” but I am like all of us imperfect.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On “the Real World”</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/01/12/on-the-fake-real-world/"/>
   <updated>2017-01-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/01/12/on-the-fake-real-world</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The news is a Category 5 shitstorm these days and it’s difficult to surface any rage-inducing story for any more than a few moments at a time. One in particular that’s driving pins into the back of my eyes is a pair of moves from Missouri and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.desmoinesregister.com/story/news/education/2017/01/12/iowa-lawmaker-looking-end-tenure-public-univerisities/96460626/&quot;&gt;Iowa to eliminate the concept of tenure in their state university systems&lt;/a&gt;. These moves come on the heels of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/sections/itsallpolitics/2015/06/12/413995691/wisconsin-gov-walkers-next-battle-tenure&quot;&gt;Wisconsin’s relatively succesful attempts&lt;/a&gt; to neuter the concept of “tenure” beyond any utility. These attacks are only going to become more and more common as increasingly Republican-led state legislatures defenstrate the American education system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not a scholar of higher education or of education more generally.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Nor am I a professor, on the tenure track or otherwise. I am a graduate student seeking a Ph.D. in English at a land-grant public university: a generally unenviable place to be in the general hierarchy of Life, I would suppose, but I enjoy it and I do pay all of my bills on time. I don’t want to talk right now about the role of tenure in higher education, because I have not experienced enough or thought on it long enough to have a considered opinion beyond “tenure is a good thing that protects vital academic discourse even as it’s a decidedly imperfect system that adversely structures the industry of academia with negative impacts on both research and the mental health of those both on and off the tenure track but that doesn’t mean we should through the baby out with the bathwater per se.” Rather I want to talk about an idea repeatedly raised in the above-linked interview with the dunderheaded Missouri congressman filing the bill to elimate tenure in that state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rick Brattin states (it’s not really an “argument” as such so I can’t use the word “argues” here) that he’s filing this bill out of concern for students in Missouri universities. He sees the university system as adversely burdening its students with too many classes that lack “real world relevance,” and sees professors as sirens luring impressionable youths into “useless” fields (which Brattin never names, but one can safely assume that we’re pulling an old-fashioned humanities vs. STEM thing again here). These students graduate with degrees in, say, English, get out into the “real world” and find they can’t get jobs and so have to go back to school burdened by debt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I cannot say this is an entirely strawman proposition because I have friends who have chosen to do just that, although never for these imagined “useless degrees” and rather because, as is their rights as Adult Humans, they realize that their interests and skills &lt;em&gt;grow and change&lt;/em&gt; over the course of a life and &lt;em&gt;it’s okay&lt;/em&gt; to change your vocation in this world after twenty-two—but I digress.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just want to meditate on the phrase “real world” for a moment. I hate it. I cannot write neutrally about it. It is a phrase filled with contempt no matter who deploys it. As a rhetorical move, it marks a space of belonging that the speaker always inhabits and the listener rarely does. It is a phrase of moral and ethical absolutes, of surety concerning how the flows of human life should run, and of faith in the superiority of a particular allocation of those flows over all else. When Brattin speaks of the real world, it is obvious what world he refers to: the world of business, of exchange, and of capital. It is a world filled with goods and services rather than ideas and impulses and feeling. (Again, I cannot write neutrally about it, I’m just too full of rage.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hate this phrase not just because of how its use implicitly devalues all that cannot be represented on the balance sheet. This is not so I can stand athwart history and say the professors and artists are the only ones who got it right. I hate this phrase because it also devalues those of us who &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; in business, in exchange, in infrastructure, in “normal,” useful jobs that make our world run.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; It presumes that people in those kinds of jobs &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; no use for art (history), written language, music, what have you. That the mass of nurses and engineers and whatever other job is &lt;em&gt;de trop&lt;/em&gt; these days don’t think about, care about, or make art in any way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that to rage at this minor phrase is perhaps missing the broader intent of this bill: to strip thinking bare so that a public becomes pliable and useful to its managerial class. I have to think, though (if only to get through the day), that such a public will always be an imaginary, and that there will always be voices, however marginalized, screaming for the value of a messy, imperfect, not-always-useful-but-always-joyous humanity. That, to me, is as close as we can get to the “real world”; it’s these dreadfully boring, managerial, capitalistic voices that seem to me more the fiction than anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Really great voices on Twitter for these sorts of things, from policy implications to on-the-ground battles, include &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tressiemcphd&quot;&gt;Tressie McMillan Cottom&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/saragoldrickrab&quot;&gt;Sara Goldrick-Rab&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rgrusin&quot;&gt;Richard Grusin&lt;/a&gt;, among many others.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;To say nothing of the fact that the last time I checked being a professor &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; an actual job that you can have that pays your bills and does exist in this spatiotemporal plane and thus is as far as we can define it, real? &lt;em&gt;But let’s just set that over here for now…&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On the Desire to Surround Oneself with Wolves</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/01/09/on-the-desire-to-surround-oneself-with-wolves/"/>
   <updated>2017-01-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/01/09/on-the-desire-to-surround-oneself-with-wolves</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Threaded tweets are bad now I guess, and the prevailing wisdom on Twitter seems to be “why are people tweeting when they could be writing blog posts?,” which I take as yet another riff on &lt;a href=&quot;https://theawl.com/youre-doing-it-wrong-b3363f192982#.qfsuifs7v&quot;&gt;“you’re doing it wrong.”&lt;/a&gt; Particularly with reports of Medium’s demise &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.medium.com/renewing-mediums-focus-98f374a960be#.tkj9k8329&quot;&gt;not really exaggerated at all&lt;/a&gt; making the space for such thoughts increasingly scarce. That being said, &lt;em&gt;I do have a blog&lt;/em&gt; so I guess I will kowtow to the times and put these thoughts here rather than as a tweetstorm. With any luck, Twitter won’t be around by the time that you read this and then I will come across as prescient rather than contrarian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last night, famous and influential (we can unpack these words later on) actor Meryl Streep gave an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/arts-and-entertainment/wp/2017/01/08/meryl-streep-called-out-donald-trump-at-the-golden-globes-read-her-speech-here/&quot;&gt;impassioned speech at the Golden Globes&lt;/a&gt; against Trump, for the rights of the oppressed, and the value of the free press. These are all excellent virtues and she is being rightfully applauded for voicing them. (Although we should be careful not to map any praise for Streep onto the Golden Globes as an awards ceremony itself, the Golden Globes being chiefly an opportunity for a variety of celebrities to crowd into a room, get drunk, and receive awards from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vox.com/2016/1/10/10741076/golden-globes-2016-hfpa-explained&quot;&gt;around ninety random white men&lt;/a&gt;.) We will undoubtedly hear more speeches like hers as the celebrity-industrial complex mobilizes, although the extent to which the celebrity-industrial complex failed to influence the election itself does make me pause as to whether or not we’re being more than a little self-congratulatory here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, Trump is a horrid, nasty, brutish individual, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/fact-checker/wp/2016/08/02/donald-trumps-revisionist-history-of-mocking-a-disabled-reporter/&quot;&gt;his callous imitation of Serge Kovaleski&lt;/a&gt; makes him unfit to be a member of our society, to say nothing of leading it. That Streep explicitly reminds us of this stomach-churning moment is to be commended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is, of course, a counter-narrative brewing on Twitter. (I would embed some tweets here but that would seem to go against the whole stop-threading-tweets thing, right? So I’m not sure where to go with that one.) It goes something like this, and we hear variations on it every time really anything happens, particularly when it involves the celebrity-industrial complex: “Stop talking about X, we should really be talking about Y.” Don’t talk about &lt;em&gt;Ellen&lt;/em&gt;, talk about Syrian refugees. It is the narrative of wrongful direction: we are not talking about the Thing We Should Be Talking About, but rather about the Thing Designed To Distract Us. (The fact that the sentence “No one is talking about Y!” explicitly &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; talking about Y will have to be left to the logicians here.) In the Age of Trump, this takes on a modified form: “X is the thing Trump &lt;em&gt;wants&lt;/em&gt; you to be talking about, and he’s distracting you from Actual Evil Thing Y!” Right now, Talking About Streep is a distraction against the impending &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2017/01/09/us/politics/confirmation-hearings-trump-press-conference.html&quot;&gt;confirmations hearings&lt;/a&gt; for Trump’s ghoulish nominations for various cabinet positions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to set aside the implication that individuals, and the aggregate of individual conversations that then constitute The Discourse®, are unable to entertain multiple trains of thought at once, and focus rather on the implicit claim within this rhetorical move: &lt;em&gt;that Trump has any agency, intelligence, or control over master narratives in any way whatsoever&lt;/em&gt;. The rhetorical move, I note, is rarely that Streep/X is distracting in a cosmic, happenstance sort of way from the Hearings/Y. Rather, it’s positioned as “Trump actively desires that we talk about Streep/X, and our conversations about it play into his larger evil plans.” The evidence for such claims usually stems from the fact that Trump, like the unstable, grasping toddler that he is, takes to Twitter to rage against the most inconsequential of imagined slights. As I write this, he is tweeting about how Streep is an “overrated” “flunky.” (He might not be wrong on the first claim?&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;) The counter-narrative, the one that claims that Trump is a media master, a Lex Luthor of misdirection, positions these tweets as a kind of eleven-dimensional chess game wherein we imagine that Trump has the wherewithal and intelligence to deliberately seize on a moment in order to shift our attention from whatever other gruesome thing it is that he is doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, I argue, is a misunderstanding of the situation, predicated on the idea that Trump is anything other than a monomaniacal buffoon. That he is one does not make him any less dangerous, but it does us all a disservice to impute skill, intelligence, and craft where there is none.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I said I wouldn’t embed a tweet but I’m going to, because this is a good one and it says everything I’m trying to say much better than I have said it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Oh this foolishness. Imputing intelligence on a fool. Yeah. They can&amp;#39;t deal with their moral system collapsing &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/wJJUO1L76Q&quot;&gt;https://t.co/wJJUO1L76Q&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Tressie Mc (@tressiemcphd) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tressiemcphd/status/817102678153134081&quot;&gt;January 5, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So: why am I getting up in arms about this particular semantic quibble? I suppose it’s because I’m a Words Person, and so I believe that calling something what it is is difficult and useful work, because it forces us to examine what it is that we’re saying &lt;em&gt;around&lt;/em&gt; what it is we think we’re saying. Trump is not tricking us into doing anything. He is not a wolf and we are not sheep. If he is a wolf, it is only because we are calling him one, and I have to pause and ask what we gain from calling him one. What do we gain from assuming that he is a cartoon supervillain? What do we win by characterizing a moment where a &lt;a href=&quot;http://people.com/politics/trump-graydon-carter-feud-vanity-fair-editor-anna-wintour/&quot;&gt;short-fingered vulgarian&lt;/a&gt; lashes out irrationally at a respected and prominent actor when she says some usefully benign things as a layered plot of the deep state?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t pretend to have any answers, but I think we gain an enemy, and we position that enemy within master narratives with which we are comfortable. Maybe this is the celebrity-industrial complex’s fault, but given how prominent a human trait it is to pit good against evil I have a hard time seeing this as anything other than we perhaps imagining ourselves to be more complex and modern than we really are. I think this is a similar reason we are revanching the Russia-as-nemesis narrative: the United States (no matter who you are within it, no matter your perspective on left, right, or center it would seem) needs an enemy. As I wrote in a tweet a few weeks back (I know, I know): “without an enemy against which to assert empire, what are we” as a nation? I wrote that tweet in response to a wave of media sentiment against Russia’s cultural achievements: they made nothing but petty cronyism, so the claims went, whereas here in America we made Great Things. (Which, you don’t even really &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to go back to the nineteenth century to get great Russian art: hell, you don’t even need to go back to the &lt;em&gt;twentieth&lt;/em&gt; century, but I stand down here.) It seems useful in this moment as well. I would not for a moment claim that these critics &lt;em&gt;desire&lt;/em&gt; Trump. I would simply ask what such claims mask: what desires live beneath. Desires for stability and coherence, certainly—it would make more &lt;em&gt;sense&lt;/em&gt; if our rulers were in fact all-powerful sociopaths against whom we could organize coherently. Tressie McMillan Cottom’s tweet usefully exposes a desire for white male supremacy: Trump’s whiteness and maleness means that he &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; have some intelligent master plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ask us to identify and name these desires so that we might more effectively name what we are really up against. This will be long and arduous work and I do not pretend to be really up to it. But I thought it might be worth starting to call some things what they seem to be now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Meryl Streep’s last truly transcendent performance was in &lt;em&gt;The Devil Wears Prada&lt;/em&gt;, this is a fact, don’t @ me.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title><i>Galatea</i> and the Play of Self-Disclosure</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/11/01/galatea-and-play/"/>
   <updated>2016-11-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2016/11/01/galatea-and-play</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Another syndicated piece of writing, this time from Matthew Kirschenbaum and Neil Fraistat’s seminar on the nonhuman.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start with the original “Galatea” myth, codified in Ovid: Pygmalion of Cyprus sculpts a beautiful white statue with which he falls in love.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; (The whiteness is important here: both in the name “Galatea,” glossed both as “goddess of calm seas” or “goddess of milk-white,” &lt;em&gt;galaktos&lt;/em&gt; the root of our word &lt;em&gt;galaxy&lt;/em&gt;, the Milky Way, and a play on mother’s milk;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and in the blankness of white, soon to be literally interpellated, called-into-being.) He begs Aphrodite to bring the statue to life; she does so, and then weds them. This origin story, like &lt;em&gt;Frankenstein&lt;/em&gt;, has proved remarkably durable and malleable, rich in allusive potential and psychosexual suggestion. It has echoed down through Western culture in different forms and names, perhaps most famously in George Bernard Shaw’s 1913 play &lt;em&gt;Pygmalion&lt;/em&gt; and its 1956 stage musical adaptation &lt;em&gt;My Fair Lady&lt;/em&gt; (note the possessive in the title). The allusive web grows more tangled when in 1964 computer scientist Joseph Weizenbaum names his early chatter bot program ELIZA after Shaw’s protagonist. ELIZA uses natural language processing to simulate a Rogerian therapist, feigning “intelligence” by turning user input back into questions, drawing a “conversation” along. Weizenbaum would approve of my scare quotes: he built the program in part to demonstrate the futility of human-computer conversation. He was shocked, however, to find that many people (including, famously, his secretary, who asked him to leave the program and her alone for a private conversation) found the illusion quite persuasive.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emily Short’s &lt;em&gt;Galatea&lt;/em&gt; (2000) stages and complicates both of these origin stories, through the form of interactive fiction (IF), a computational literature and gaming genre more closely related to a different myth: the Minoan labyrinth.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Not for nothing did IF scholar Nick Montfort title his book-length history and poetics of the form &lt;em&gt;Twisty Little Passages&lt;/em&gt;; from the genre’s earliest instantiations in mainframe computer text adventure games like &lt;em&gt;Adventure&lt;/em&gt; (1970) and &lt;em&gt;Zork&lt;/em&gt; (1977–79), interactive fiction almost always means mazes. But Short doesn’t give us a typical maze: &lt;em&gt;Galatea&lt;/em&gt; takes place in just one room, and the archetypal IF compass directional commands only return the provocation, “If you want to leave, just say so.” Nor is &lt;em&gt;Galatea&lt;/em&gt; designed with the typical IF programming, as Montfort observes that the piece’s technical contribution to IF is not any sophistication in recognizing and responding to diverse input, as one might expect from a piece entering into dialogue with the history of chat bots, but rather its “complex discourse model and an emotional model, with variables for Galatea’s mod, her sympathy with the player character, and the amount of tension” (219). Our maze, it would seem, is not spatial, but sensual. Crucially, with its idiosyncratic implementation of &lt;em&gt;generative&lt;/em&gt; branching paths keyed to emotional states rather than spatial triggers, &lt;em&gt;Galatea&lt;/em&gt; destabilizes typical understandings of not only what a maze in IF might be, but how to navigate—players can move forward and around, but never back. The piece characterizes the interaction of intelligences as a constantly shifting terrain, and new possibilities emerge as other doors are shut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, unlike real life, we can turn &lt;em&gt;Galatea&lt;/em&gt; off and on again and try for new routes; the game’s profusion of distinct endings would seem to promote this kind of extratextual engagement. Indeed, repetition and duration become key tactics by which to explore Galatea’s “personality.” But the longer that a play session goes, the more obscure, it seems, Galatea-the-character becomes. To quote games theorist Ian Bogost quoting philosopher Graham Harman, “there is always something that recedes—always hidden, inside, inaccessible” (6). Bogost is discussing objects here, and the ways that objects, ontologically-speaking, “recede” from examination, always withholding expressive and relational potential; the suggestive possibility then is that “stuffs [sic] enjoy equal being no matter their size, scale, or order” (6). I take this brief object-orientated ontological turn mostly for its reflective value: these ideas, applied to &lt;em&gt;Galatea&lt;/em&gt;, seem to me to be a useful frame through which to understand how we as players are locked in a kind of mutual interpellation with the interactive object. As we search for Galatea’s &lt;em&gt;Dasein&lt;/em&gt;, we also uncover and admit things about ourselves. &lt;em&gt;Galatea&lt;/em&gt; thematizes this on two levels: the first in the extent to which the player’s avatar is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; blank—as I uncover things about Galatea I-the-player also uncover things about me-the-avatar, the two beginning to merge through the act of &lt;em&gt;parsing&lt;/em&gt;; the second, in the potential for &lt;em&gt;Galatea&lt;/em&gt;/Galatea to operate as a direct descendent of ELIZA, prompting me-as-player to reveal things &lt;em&gt;about&lt;/em&gt; myself &lt;em&gt;to&lt;/em&gt; myself. Example: I was loath to use the “TOUCH,” “SMELL,” or “TASTE” commands—they felt rude and transgressive in ways I was unwilling to engage at first. As I grew frustrated with how Galatea “receded” from my apprehension, I came to realize that paths forward might exist in those actions or thoughts that I “hid” from the program. And really, who is doing the real prompting here? Who is suggesting, and who is responding? Short knows that this question is perhaps the most central to IF as a form, and &lt;em&gt;Galatea&lt;/em&gt;’s achievement might be how it reflects these concerns back out to the players: the “problem” of the game may not be that Galatea cannot understand us, but that we cannot understand Galatea, or perhaps that we cannot understand how to make ourselves understood to her. We can only detect micronic ripples in an emotional substrate running underneath, prompting &lt;em&gt;us&lt;/em&gt; (for who is the prompt really for?) to further action and disclosure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;citations-for-the-interested&quot;&gt;Citations for the Interested&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bogost, Ian. &lt;em&gt;Alien Phenomenology, or What It’s Like to Be a Thing&lt;/em&gt;. U of Minnesota P, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Montfort, Nick. &lt;em&gt;Twisty Little Passages: An Approach to Interactive Fiction&lt;/em&gt;. MIT P, 2003.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.poetryintranslation.com/PITBR/Latin/Metamorph10.htm#anchor_Toc64105570&quot;&gt;Link here.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galatea_(mythology)#cite_ref-1&quot;&gt;The link&lt;/a&gt; to the Smith Classics Dictionary seems to be down], but “gala” as milk &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/γάλα#Greek&quot;&gt;seems to check out&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;This is drawn from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ELIZA&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ELIZA&lt;/a&gt;, much of which in turn is drawn from Weizenbaum’s book &lt;em&gt;Computer Power and Human Reason: From Judgment to Calculation&lt;/em&gt;, W. H. Freeman, 1976 (yes, it seems that people taking ELIZA seriously disturbed Weizenbaum so much that he wrote a whole book about it!)&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;For an &lt;em&gt;excellent&lt;/em&gt; book on the labyrinth and computing, check out Montfort, Nick et al. &lt;em&gt;10 PRINT CHR$(205.5+RND(1)); : GOTO 10&lt;/em&gt;. MIT P, 2013. &lt;a href=&quot;http://10print.org&quot;&gt;http://10print.org&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Corrupting Books’ Flesh and Blood</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/09/11/corrupting-books-flesh-blood/"/>
   <updated>2016-09-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2016/09/11/corrupting-books-flesh-blood</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I have a lot of writing to do in grad school, and I want to get better about making more of it public. So for regular blog post and short essay assignments, I’m going to syndicate some of them across to my personal blog. Here’s one from&lt;/em&gt; ENGL718C: From Manuscript to Print: Medieval and Early Modern Histories of the Book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to be a book in 1344. If you’re lucky, you have an aristocratic patron like Richard de Bury, who venerates you above all other riches in the world and ensures your physical safety for as long as he (and I’m going to assume here that your reader or owner—Thomas here encouraging us to note the distinction, particularly given aftermarkets of sale and resale emerging in the 13th and 14th centuries (150)—was invariably a “he”) lives. Then again, you might not be so lucky. You might “suffer from various diseases, endur[e] pains in [your] backs and sides…[and] lie with [your] limbs unstrung by palsy.” “Smoke and dust” may “dul[l] the keenness of your visual rays [and] infec[t your] bleared eyes with ophthalmia.” Worms may “devour” your organs. In neglect, you may be sold off and “lie as hostages in taverns,” or worse, in the hands of “Jews, Saracens, heretics, and infidels.” Even if you manage to stay put in a monastery, the “purity of [your] race” may “diminish every day” by successive “compilers, translators, and transformers,” reducing you to a “degenerate” (de Bury 19-20 [chpt 4]).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I indulge in this extended quotation to explore the particular physicality, often intensely gendered, that de Bury endues to books as objects, often in contrast to those same books’ role as perfect and immortal vessels of pure knowledge. The &lt;em&gt;Philobiblon&lt;/em&gt;’s fourth chapter, a “complaint of books against the clergy,” climaxes in the images I’ve quoted above: books with limbs that can palsy, eyes that can fade, organs that can rot—a body that can be sold off and “diminished” in infidel hands. The book’s body is distinctly feminized, and many of the same cultural anxieties and obsessions around purity and virginity that apply to masculine discussions of women’s bodies clearly map onto de Bury’s treatment here. It’s fascinating to me that the chapter’s litany of “corruptions” climaxes with the worst of all: that the book’s sense may be diluted over generations of copyists’ errors or willful emendations (in contrast to the iron-tight Taylorist ateliers Thomas describes and in concert with ideas of pirating from Darnton).&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could go on with examples of “despoiled” bodies and the need for books’ “gradual perfecting” from across the &lt;em&gt;Philobiblon&lt;/em&gt;—chapters 10 and 16 are particularly rich sources—but want to turn briefly to Stallybrass’s ideas of indexicality as a way to think through this anxiety in formal and material terms. Indexicality and “discontinuous reading” are, in Stallybrass’s argument, the codex’s key innovation and a source of doctrinal strife (46–7). In particular, I think of the story of Protestant martyr Anne Askew, whose deliberate practice of “detach[ing]” and “arrang[ing]” Biblical quotations to construct theological arguments would, I would expect, inflame de Bury’s anxiety around a book’s purity of sense—that the book’s lesson (frequently detached, in the &lt;em&gt;Philobiblon&lt;/em&gt;, from its author, unless that author is Aristotle!) be coherent and proceed unidirectionally (Stallybrass 70–1).&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; “Corruption,” in this rubric, is not just physical decay, but what happens when a broader reading public gets its hands on books and starts doing things with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;citations-for-the-interested&quot;&gt;Citations for the Interested&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;de Bury, Richard. &lt;em&gt;The Love of Books: Philobiblon of Richard de Bury.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Project Gutenberg&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/626&quot;&gt;www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/626&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Darnton, Robert. “What is the History of Books?” 1982. The Book History Reader, 2nd ed., edited by David Finkelstein and Alistair McCleery, Routledge, 2006, pp. 9–26. Originally in Daedalus, Summer 1982, pp. 65–83.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stallybrass, Peter. “Books and Scrolls: Navigating the Bible” Books and Readers in Early Modern England: Material Studies, edited by Jenny Anderson, U of Philadelphia Press, 2002, pp. 42–79.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thomas, Marcel. “Manuscripts.” 1986. The Book History Reader, 2nd ed., edited by David Finkelstein and Alistair McCleery, Routledge, 2006, pp. 147-55.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;To say nothing of the fact that his devotional fetish for books does not infrequently resemble that of a tyrannical husband keeping his wife locked up “for her own safety.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I also take special pleasure in noting that something resembling modern citational practice so inflamed the Church at the time!&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Minimalism and Computing</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/08/25/minimalism-computing/"/>
   <updated>2016-08-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2016/08/25/minimalism-computing</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few weeks late on the hot take treadmill to this piece, although I was on writing hiatus so I get temporary immunity. From Kyle Chayka’s “The Oppressive Gospel of Minimalism,” back in the &lt;em&gt;New York Times Magazine&lt;/em&gt; at the end of July:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Despite its connotations of absence, “minimalism” has been popping up everywhere lately, like a bright algae bloom in the murk of postrecession America. From tiny houses to microapartments to monochromatic clothing to interior-decorating trends — picture white walls interrupted only by succulents — less now goes further than ever. It’s easy to feel overwhelmed by the minimalism glut, as the word can be applied to just about anything. The nearly four million images tagged #minimalism on Instagram include white sneakers, clouds, the works of Mondrian, neon signs, crumbling brick walls and grassy fields. So long as it’s stylishly austere, it seems, it’s minimalist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chayka’s essay takes on a particular manifestation of “minimalism,” divorced, as he writes, from the historical and cultural specificity of minimal turns in the 1960’s by visual and sonic artists like Donald Judd or Philip Glass (neither of whom associated themselves with the term—I particularly love Glass’s description of his work as “music with repetitive structures) and put towards a Silicon Valley aesthetic of absence, flatness, and carefully cultivated consumption. Consumerist minimalism, in this logic, isn’t really about aesthetics itself, but about using key aesthetic cues (symmetry, planar geometry, vague grey and brushed aluminum) to indicate that you’re living a particular lifestyle. (And it goes without saying that that lifestyle is &lt;em&gt;expensive&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it’s interesting to set Chayka’s critiques alongside a turn in digital humanities theory and praxis that I’ve been seeing swell up a bit recently around &lt;em&gt;minimal computing&lt;/em&gt;. Minimalism as a virtue in computing is nothing new: exhortations to write “elegant” or “beautiful” code are more or less shibboleths for programs that are internally and syntactically consistent, technically efficient with regard to processing power, and as short as possible—code à la Raymond Carver. Minimal computing, as mapped by a GO::DH working group on the idea at the mega-DH conference in Lausanne in 2014, focuses more on the political and ecological ramifications of computing constraints, as well as the ways that forced constraints echo back to different modes of relating to technology and digital work from across computing’s history. To wit, &lt;a href=&quot;http://go-dh.github.io/mincomp/about/&quot;&gt;from the working group’s website&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We use “minimal computing” to refer to computing done under some set of significant constraints of hardware, software, education, network capacity, power, or other factors. Minimal computing includes both the maintenance, refurbishing, and use of machines to do DH work out of necessity along with the use of new streamlined computing hardware like the Raspberry Pi or the Arduino micro controller to do DH work by choice…. In this way minimal computing is also a critical movement, akin to environmentalism, asking for balance between gains and costs in related areas that include social justice issues and de-manufacturing and reuse, not to mention re-thinking high-income assumptions about “e-waste” and what people do with it. Minimal computing thus relates to issues of aesthetics, culture, environment, global relationships of power and knowledge production, and other economic, infrastructural and material conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are all aims that I find valiant and necessary, particularly around thinking through the “global relationships of power and knowledge production,” particularly when those relationships involve asymmetries of ecological burden. Something I have trouble reconciling in my own practice (especially as someone who tends to gravitate towards technological or lifestyle “minimalism” in my day-to-day life) is the tension between minimalism-by-choice and minimalism-by-force. Put another way: self-imposed austerity, by virtue of being self-imposed, is always temporary. As Chayka writes, “…it takes a lot to be minimalist: social capital, a safety net and access to the internet. The technology we call minimalist might fit in our pockets, but it depends on a vast infrastructure of grim, air-conditioned server farms and even grimmer Chinese factories.” Even something as small and pared-back as the Raspberry Pi (I have a few scattered around my apartment, happily buzzing away in their cute pre-fab plastic cases) depends on a supply chain unknown to me, that almost certainly reverberates in decidedly &lt;em&gt;un&lt;/em&gt;-minimalist ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most interesting attempts at a praxis of “local, sustainable” computing comes from Nathan Schneider’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://newrepublic.com/article/121832/pleasure-do-it-yourself-slow-computing&quot;&gt;“The Joy of Slow Computing”&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;em&gt;The New Republic&lt;/em&gt; last year, which works through various self-hosted and software cooperative approaches to computing in order to develop a practice of “slow computing” à la slow food or slow TV. Schneider’s article is a fascinating provocation and becomes even more interesting when taken alongside Schneider’s heavy involvement in Trebor Scholz and others’ &lt;a href=&quot;http://platformcoop.net&quot;&gt;platform cooperativism movement&lt;/a&gt;. And all of them resonate with both &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.publicseminar.org/2015/11/theory-for-the-anthropocene/&quot;&gt;Roy Scranton’s and Stephanie Wakefield’s calls for a reduced or transformed human existence&lt;/a&gt; in the wake of anthropogenic climate change. In this lens, the work of developing a “theory for the Anthropocene” becomes key for me in reconciling the idea of “forced austerity”—it’s an oncoming austerity that is our shared responsibility as humans, and one that we as scholars, artists, and thinkers can take as a transfigurative challenge for the current moment.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Quick Notes on Resource Extractions</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/08/24/quick-notes-on-resource-extractions/"/>
   <updated>2016-08-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2016/08/24/quick-notes-on-resource-extractions</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of my first assigned readings in graduate school is Bruce Holsinger’s “Of Pigs and Parchment: Medieval Studies and the Coming of the Animal,” (2009) a short &lt;em&gt;cri de cœur&lt;/em&gt; exhorting Medieval studies and the study of the history of the book to grapple concertedly with the simple fact that parchment culture depended on the mass slaughter of non-human animals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a remarkable essay, full of small moments Shklovsky-esque estrangement from Western print and animal cultures. In particular, I was struck by how the sheer scale of skin necessary to produce a single codex revealed the economic (really, subsistence!) underpinnings of a culture for whom books were simultaneously invaluably precious and barely a part of everyday life:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Many medievalists trained in paleography will recall Bernhard Bischoff’s sobering observation about the quantity of skins needed for particularly large books: “For the production of the Codex Amiatinus alone—and it had two sister manuscripts—over 500 sheepskins were required at Wearmouth or Jarrow” (10). Yet we rarely let ourselves think in a sustained way about the economies of scale and animal consumption that allowed for the transmission of medieval literature: the reduction of entire flocks, indeed by some estimates whole villages of animals, into a single book. (Holsinger 619)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the choice between feeding a family or a village and producing print culture, even in 2016 and working towards a PhD in English Literature, I’d choose the former every time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This turn resonates across recent popular strands of thought in media studies, epitomized for me best by Jussi Parikka’s recent &lt;em&gt;A Geology of Media&lt;/em&gt; (2015), that foreground digital media’s supply chains and production cultures in order to point towards the ecological underpinnings and reverberations of contemporary computing technologies.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; As media studies increasingly considers the known-but-not-known-enough-to-be-troubling (c.f. factory farming) ecological and ethical ramifications of supply chains like coltan mining in the Congo and toxic waste deposition in China, or the precarious in all senses of the word human labor assembling devices in Foxconn in Shenzhen (just to rehearse a few common touchstones), Holsinger’s turn reminds us all in comparative media studies that production is always built on the exploitation of things-perceived-to-be-resources, whether those things are oil, soil, animals, or our fellow humans. Indeed, the thing that Holsinger’s essay starts to crack for me is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; pointing to a cycle of exploitation—old hat in the academy, but still worth underscoring as frequently as possible—but the hyphenate idea from that previous sentence: things-perceived-to-be-resources. What are the limits of us understanding capital-but-also-I-guess-lowercase-T Things &lt;em&gt;qua&lt;/em&gt; object oriented ontology as potential resources to be transformed, transmuted, and transfigured into other Things that are of higher utility to us humans? How can media studies address the role of suffering and pain in these transformations—particularly when the suffering is potentially beyond our current abilities to perceive and understand, as with animals, or even, as Parikka provocatively suggests (taking up Reza Negarestani’s astonishing novel &lt;em&gt;Cyclonopedia: Complicity with Anonymous Materials&lt;/em&gt; [2008]), the earth itself?&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;citations-for-the-interested&quot;&gt;Citations for the Interested&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holsinger, Bruce. &lt;em&gt;Music, Body, and Desire in Medieval Culture&lt;/em&gt;. Stanford UP, 2001.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–––. “Of Pigs and Parchment: Medieval Studies and the Coming of the Animal.” &lt;em&gt;PMLA&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 124, no. 2, March 2009, pp. 616–623.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Negarestani, Reza. &lt;em&gt;Cyclonopedia: Complicity with Anonymous Materials&lt;/em&gt;. Re:press, 2008.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parikka, Jussi. &lt;em&gt;A Geology of Media&lt;/em&gt;. University of Minnesota Press, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Or, on a lighter-but-still-vastly-terrifying-note, when I recently learned after moving into a new apartment and furnishing it almost exclusively in tastefully anonymous Scandinavian decor, that &lt;a href=&quot;http://gizmodo.com/ikea-uses-a-staggering-one-percent-of-the-worlds-wood-677540490&quot;&gt;IKEA uses nearly one percent of the world’s total wood production&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;For a later post: after I read through this essay I remembered that I had encountered Holsinger before, in a seminar on word, life, and image in undergrad, for which I wrote a term paper drawing heavily from his &lt;em&gt;Music, Body, and Desire in Medieval Culture&lt;/em&gt; (2001) to think through how Medieval musical notation operated to dissolve, erase, or transform individual performers in devotional practice—chiefly through physical pain.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On Putting Words on the Internet</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/08/23/on-putting-words-on-the-internet/"/>
   <updated>2016-08-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2016/08/23/on-putting-words-on-the-internet</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Enough pixels have already been spilled on 2016, The Worst Year Ever. These pixels have also been thoroughly rejoined by an ostensibly different but ontologically similar set of pixels declaring that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slate.com/articles/news_and_politics/history/2016/07/is_2016_the_worst_year_in_history.html&quot;&gt;“no, the Black Death was &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; much worse, y’all”&lt;/a&gt;, which is &lt;em&gt;a&lt;/em&gt; point but perhaps not &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at the end of August in a year in which we’ve lost a number of key inspirational artists, another dozen(s) of Black lives to police killings, slogged on (here in the United States at least) with a presidential race that has brought out the worst (or at least the most callous and bitchiest) of most of us, about the only thing that we can truly say for certain is that it’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2016/08/20/sunday-review/climate-change-hot-future.html?_r=2&quot;&gt;getting hotter, fast&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But another thing we lost in 2016: the blog as a sustainable media venture. Back in 2013 we had a great site, &lt;a href=&quot;http://thedissolve.com&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Dissolve&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which had a number of blind spots, particularly around non-Anglo films and hiring women and people of color, but that was a dramatic, sophisticated level up on the press-release-and-breathless-set-photographs that define much of film criticism (or at least conversation) online. Until this July we had &lt;a href=&quot;http://the-toast.net&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Toast&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a kind of niche site for thoughtful librarians and medievalists that we used to have a lot more of, until a kind of metrics-based homogenization swept the web. And until yesterday we had &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gawker.com&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gawker&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;—good old &lt;em&gt;Gawker&lt;/em&gt;, which maybe you hated but you can’t deny defined what it meant to write on the Internet for more than a decade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was not conscious witness to the first wave of blogs—I was too young. The second wave of blogs, perhaps the one that I’m mourning in a way, weren’t blogs you started in the middle of the night and then furiously deleted by morning,&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; but were more like alt-weeklies—strange, specific voices that churned things out a little too fast and a little too loud, and then burned off into the night when the time came and the money ran out. I don’t mourn a publication disappearing—more things should go gently into that good night, I suppose, particularly in media. But what I do mourn is the loss of an atmosphere of possibility—we lost these sites, and others like them, mostly because no one except possibly Google and Facebook have figured out how to make a living writing words on the Internet and letting other people read them. Or we do write on the Internet every day, but just for individuated social networks with particular formal or audience constraints. Hell, I turned analytics off on this site because I was uninterested in knowing precisely how few people are able to find things organically on the Internet these days.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2016 is not the worst year ever, because the worst year ever is whenever the inevitable heat death of the Universe obliterates what is left of the last dregs of the evolutionary chain to which we (although c’mon, it’s not gonna be us, it’s gonna be roaches or something, all hail the mighty roach) are parents. But 2016 increasingly feels like a Rubicon of…&lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;. At least we’ll always have dinky sites like this one to whinge about it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I had my own share of those—mostly single-entry Blogger sites that I’d anonymously pour drek into, and once tentatively shared the link with a friend, who left a this-is-utter-shit comment on a post (totally warranted, it &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; utter shit, but we were also fourteen, so?) and I learned then and there that I was not &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; cut out for publishing things On Line.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;RIP Google Reader.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On Post-Baccalaureate Residencies</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/06/30/on-postbaccalaureate-residencies/"/>
   <updated>2016-06-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2016/06/30/on-postbaccalaureate-residencies</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today is my last day as Five College Post-Baccalaureate Resident in Digital Humanities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s do the numbers: I’ve worked for Five College Digital Humanities for three years, over which I’ve assisted around fifteen faculty and staff projects, supervised sixteen student fellows, taught three January-term classes, submitted around a hundred check requests, sat in a dozen or so Steering Committee Meetings, been on three or four hiring committees, ran a floating gallery, improved my tech skills by several orders of magnitude, given five talks, administered an unspeakable number of Slack rooms, and overseen the production of around thirty gigabytes of video, audio, and other media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These numbers are neither impressive nor remarkable in the scale of what knowledge labor looks like in 2016, but they do strike me as constituting an unusual spread of activities in academia for someone fresh out of undergrad. My time with Five College Digital Humanities has been singularly rewarding, particularly for the ways that I’ve been given free rein to build my job in whatever way made sense at the time, and as I’ve come to the end of this last year, a number of administrators, faculty, and students interested in this admittedly weird hybrid job have asked me to put together some thoughts on what post-bacs actually &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt;, and what others might want to think about doing when putting together jobs such as mine. So, dutifully, and because I’m a sucker for a writing prompt, here are some thoughts!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started this job fresh out of undergrad in the summer of 2013, neither I nor most anyone I met had a clear idea what it was supposed to be. Five College Digital Humanities had existed for a couple of years, and had focused originally on funding faculty and staff projects. It was an insular program by design, one tasked with slowly building capital for itself and the digital humanities as a practice more generally. The idea of a “post-bac” was never a part of the original grant; the Steering Committee at the time dreamed it up, in concert with a more tradition post-doc position, as a way to fulfill, if not in exact letter at least in spirit, the grant’s goals of increased research presence and community engagement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My initial job description was a masterstroke of purposeful vagueness, and is, I think, worth sharing here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;…[Y]ou will collaborate with students, faculty members, librarians and information and education technology staff members from multiple campuses on a range of projects engaging digital technology in the study and teaching of the humanities…Your work will include helping to shape conceptual approaches to scholarly questions, but also assisting in the application of digital technology. In addition to collaborating on selected current projects, you will be expected to undertake an independent project during the appointment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a tall order of a job, and one that puts a tremendous amount of trust in someone who, by definition, doesn’t really know that much about anything! I was the first post-bac that a Five College grant had hired, and while each of the campuses had some precedent for hiring recent grads in various capacities, none had taken such a research- and skills-development focus as my job. My day-to-day work was always in negotiation depending on the grant’s priorities, extant projects, and whether or not we had other post-bacs working with us. My first year was a tectonic one for the grant: we started branching out beyond just funding faculty and staff projects through our student fellowship program; we got &lt;a href=&quot;http://5colldh.org&quot;&gt;a seriously larger website&lt;/a&gt; off the ground; we laid the groundwork for hiring more post-bacs in the two years to come; and we switched out faculty Directors and numerous Steering Committee members. In all of these expansions, retractions, and shifts, I became a kind of brain trust for the grant, keeping track off all the moving pieces. I knew who was doing what kinds of work on each campus; I knew how to connect people doing parallel things. I had the time and the wherewithal to schedule meetings, make sure catering showed up when it was supposed to, and take on mentoring student fellows. It made sense: I was the only person whose full-time pre-occupation was Five College Digital Humanities. Everyone else had day jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the second year, we had hired two more post-bacs with more specialized focuses: Kim Bain, a masterful events orchestrator, took over running our speaker series and pooling some of the student-facing energies with me; and Mariel Nyröp (who at the time of this writing is staying on another year with 5CollDH) joined us as a technologist. From a labor perspective, this was crucial. As 5CollDH expanded, my day-to-day work was beginning to consume the time I ordinarily had blocked off for research projects. At first, this didn’t feel like a big deal—the research was just one component of the job, and it was natural that its day-to-day place would wax and wane. But it became clear that not only was the workload really threatening to eclipse the research, it was in fact the research that made the job useful, interesting, and worth having. Bringing on more post-bacs allowed us to split the administrative work in such a way that research could once again occupy a larger part of all of our time—to help us “shape approaches to scholarly questions”  in the digital humanities not just for us personally, but for the Five College community more generally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We grew to see the job more and more as a true residency—a temporary way-station through which our practices as scholars, artists, or whatever kind of workers and thinkers we might imagine ourselves to be, could grow and deepen. Marisa Parham, the current faculty Director of 5CollDH and my boss for the last two years, called this the “CV Test.” When any project or new task emerged for us, we asked ourselves if and how it was articulable on a CV in a way that was useful to us. This test was useful not only to usefully demarcate what kinds of work we should or should not do, but also to help us find articulable skills and experiences within even mundane tasks. I now know not only how to operate a web server: I can explain the fundamentals to you and get you set up with a website of your own in one short meeting. I know how to plan a symposium, wrangle participants, and make sure everyone gets paid on time. And I know how these and other “administrative” skills are imbricated in the work of research—how organization, execution, and articulation are the bedfellows of exploration, theory, and experimentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CV Test also usefully demarcates the duties of a post-bac as distinct from other kinds of college staff. A post-bac, unsurprisingly, commands lower pay than the average staff member. It’s therefore unsurprising that deans and other administrative types like post-bac residencies for the real benefits both for graduating students and a campus’ bottom line. Post-bacs are a potentially abundant source of cheap labor—a pool of workers who have the advantage of knowing the institution intimately but who also can be paid lower than normal staff. This is, of course, only a salient reading when post-bacs perform the same duties as administrative tasks—something that the CV Test protects against. The CV Test focuses the residency on forward propulsion, asking the post-bac, her supervisors, and the program more generally to grapple constantly with the question of “where are we going?” Furthermore, it protects against the devaluation of permanent staff, who, by the very nature of their jobs and the permanence of their contracts, will always be able to perform their duties more effectively than someone who’s coming in for a year or two (or three).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what now? I’m moving on from this gig to seek my PhD in English at the University of Maryland, College Park, where I’ll work with Matthew Kirschenbaum, Neil Fraistat, and lurk around the Maryland Institute for Technology in the Humanities while researching the history of media. It’s not exactly what I thought I’d end up doing when I started undergrad, back when my English major was something that I did to make the Theater &amp;amp; Dance major feel just a little more serious. And even then, it wasn’t an English major about technology—it was about Serious Books by Serious People, contemporary weirdos with Big Ideas about Things. And then I slipped into film studies (I mostly loved theater because I loved movies, after all)—and then I slipped into media and technology studies (if you told seven-year-old me that I could study video games in college…)—and then I got an email about Five College Digital Humanities in the late spring of my last year of undergrad (sent, I’m pretty sure, by the Theater &amp;amp; Dance Department!), and threw my hat into the ring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three years later, I owe this position for giving me the time, mentorship, and trust to test a variety of different waters—for giving me the apprenticeship in the other side of academia than undergrad simply can’t (and frankly shouldn’t). More of us should have the opportunity to muck around for a couple years and get paid doing it. I have been tremendously, unreasonably lucky in that regard. And as more post-bac-style jobs crop up for recent grads, I hope that they take the fashion mine did: research-focused, with strong mentorship, and just the right amount of freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Plastic, Logic, and Time — A Lightning Talk</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/05/03/showcase-plastic-logic-time/"/>
   <updated>2016-05-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2016/05/03/showcase-plastic-logic-time</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the blog version of a lightning talk that I’ve given a few times at Five College Digital Humanities and the Maryland Institute for Technology in the Humanities.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a talk about three hundred and thirty one bytes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/showcase-smw.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;showcase-smw&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Still from &lt;em&gt;Super Mario World&lt;/em&gt;. Screenshot by the author. Emulated in OpenEmu 2.0.1 for OS X.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1990: Nintendo releases Super Mario World for the Super Nintendo Entertainment System. The game sells &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webcitation.org/5nXieXX2B&quot;&gt;just under fifty million copies across the world&lt;/a&gt;, and goes on to be considered, in enthusiast circles, one of the greatest platforming games ever made. It receives numerous re-releases both as physical ports and downloadable software, the most recent of which was for the Nintendo 3DS this past March.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/showcase-flappy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;showcase-flappy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Still from &lt;em&gt;Flappy Bird&lt;/em&gt;. Screenshot from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fQoJZuBwrkU&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;IGN&lt;/a&gt;. Run in iOS 7.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013: Vietnamese games developer Nguyen Ha Dong releases Flappy Bird to the iOS App Store. The simple sidescroller is punishingly difficult not because of any innate gameplay sophistication, but because of its crude design. If you’ve played it, you know: players navigate a small, flappy bird through a series of Mario-esque pipes. Hit the pipe and you drop dead. The game achieves sudden, immense popularity in early 2014 and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/2014/2/5/5383708/flappy-bird-revenue-50-k-per-day-dong-nguyen-interview&quot;&gt;makes upwards of $50,000 a day on in-app advertising&lt;/a&gt;. On February 10th, 2014, Nguyen abruptly pulls the game from all platforms, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rollingstone.com/culture/news/the-flight-of-the-birdman-flappy-bird-creator-dong-nguyen-speaks-out-20140311&quot;&gt;citing concerns that his game was taking over people’s lives&lt;/a&gt;. Phones with Flappy Bird still installed routinely sell on eBay for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2014/feb/10/phones-flappy-bird-ebay-app-store&quot;&gt;thousands of dollars&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;428&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hB6eY73sLV0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hB6eY73sLV0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Link.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2016: Prolific YouTube streamer SethBling releases a video demonstrating how, using a series of glitches and graphical exploits present in the original console release of Super Mario World, he managed to transform the game into an ad hoc computer in and of itself, and with timed jumps and button presses, write three hundred and thirty one bytes of data into the system’s RAM—data corresponding to the original source code of Flappy Bird. The exploit allows players to play a fully-functional port of Flappy Bird inside Super Mario World, grafting the former’s gameplay logic onto the latter’s graphics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what do we make of this, apart from a testament to the powers of obsession? We remember Flappy Bird for all the wrong reasons, it would seem: it’s a terribly-made game, a bizarre success, and one that was forcibly disappeared at the height of its inexplicable popularity. SethBling’s hack produces a hybrid object, a chimaera of logic, plastic, and time, a ghost of one game haunting the shell of another. It reveals “memory” as a function of physical hardware, the rhetoric of software, and the transmission of shared culture. I think of Wendy Chun’s idea of software’s “enduring ephemerality,” the capacity of computational media to “remember” through material regeneration—continual acts of writing and rewriting information across electrical charges and silicon. This hack is rewriting, and its ingenious recycling of those three hundred and thirty one bytes embodies Chun’s claim that “what is not constantly upgraded or ‘migrated’ or both becomes unreadable…The experiences of using—the exact paths of execution—are ephemeral. Information is ‘undead’: neither alive or dead, neither quite present or absent.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/showcase-snes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;showcase-snes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;A North American Super Nintendo Entertainment System. Image from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Super_Nintendo_Entertainment_System#/media/File:SNES-Mod1-Console-Set.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wikimedia Commons.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s “bare metal,” a systems engineer might say: a simple as computing gets. Physical button presses inscribe assembly code—one abstraction up from zeroes and ones, which are in turn one abstraction up from positively and negatively charged circuits. But it’s not all binary: we see gaps, cracks, and accidents through which to expose computation’s physical substrates, to manipulate the material ecologies of our devices. In the end, all things decay, but never in the ways we expect. I keep a Super Nintendo in my office right over there, and I’ve brought it out for show-and-tell now. The Super Nintendo’s casing and internals are made of a number of different kinds of plastic and metal. Most of it is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.plasticseurope.org/what-is-plastic/types-of-plastics-11148/engineering-plastics/abs.aspx&quot;&gt;acrylonitrile butadiene styrene&lt;/a&gt;, or ABS. It’s the same plastic in LEGOs, 3D printing, and the casing of most electronics. It is petroleum-based and non-biodegradable: effectively immortal. But this immortality is deceptive: metal contacts tarnish around it, the fuzzy charges of circuitry wear down, and the inevitable entropy sets in. We can say that ideas, languages, rhetorics, instructions—code—may last. They won’t. They too are dependent on systems that decay. Systems of recording, systems of remembering, systems contingent not just on technology, but also how we play with them. Code mutates, but never in the ways that we expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s one thing I learned in my research about ABS, that plastic in consoles, cartridges, and the Great Pacific Garbage Path, that I thought was interesting, that gave me some hope. Like those three hundred and thirty one bytes, it is highly recyclable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Wendy Hui Kyong Chun, &lt;em&gt;Programmed Visions: Software and Memory&lt;/em&gt; (Cambridge: The MIT Press, 2011), 133.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A semi-comprehensive list of my obsessions circa April 11th, 2016</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/04/11/obsessions-circa-april11/"/>
   <updated>2016-04-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2016/04/11/obsessions-circa-april11</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In a brief moment of calm that is the onslaught of April in academia (although I hope this week to finally finish up some of the posts that have been sitting in my drafts folder for months now), a few things I can’t stop thinking about:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;anna-merediths-varmints&quot;&gt;Anna Meredith’s &lt;em&gt;Varmints&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe class=&quot;embed-no-caption&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/57099033&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This track is from 2012 and I’m only just hearing it now off the Scottish composer Anna Meredith’s first full-length &lt;em&gt;Varmints&lt;/em&gt;. I’ve been slipping into listening to more and more electronic and synth-driven music over the past few months (be glad I didn’t write this post last week when Yaz’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LIiyT67Sjbg&quot;&gt;“Only You”&lt;/a&gt; was inexplicably in rotation for me, probably because of a scene in Thing Obsession #3), and “Nautilus” arrived as a revelation for me. The way the beat comes in about three-quarters of the way through and terraforms your understanding of the interlocking horns; this is a song of swagger and menace and vibrancy, and while the whole album doesn’t (how could it?) live up to the opening track’s highs, it’s still a hell of a high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-raspberry-pi&quot;&gt;My Raspberry Pi&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love this little thing. I finally bought one after years of dithering about not having a project to run on it, until I found the &lt;a href=&quot;http://retropie.org.uk&quot;&gt;RetroPie&lt;/a&gt; project and some incredible software history torrents on the Internet Archive. And you know what? It’s still a joyously useless piece of hardware. It sits next to my TV, and sometimes I remember to hook it up and play &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3wOFyKq1RY8&quot;&gt;Hatris&lt;/a&gt;. When I turn it on, my friends joke that my TV is hacking into the Matrix. It has a cute little pink and white case. I named it Winifred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I’m working on a longer post now about the idea of “minimal computing” in DH, and how devices like the Raspberry Pi alongside a rhetorical turn to the “command line” across a number of DH and web development tools operate within contemporary cultural turns to “slowness” in, say, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Slow_television&quot;&gt;television&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slowfoodusa.org&quot;&gt;food&lt;/a&gt;. For more intel, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://go-dh.github.io/mincomp/&quot;&gt;Mincomp DH Working Group Blog&lt;/a&gt; succinctly lays out [though the site’s a bit barebones right now] the potential stakes for a turn towards computing done under constraints. More on this, hopefully, soon.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fringe&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fringe&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In lieu of sentences:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;having now finished FRINGE, can confidently back Ben Wyatt up &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/xamzr3m9YE&quot;&gt;https://t.co/xamzr3m9YE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jeffrey Moro (@jeffreymoro) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jeffreymoro/status/714505503574003712&quot;&gt;March 28, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;a show like that had no business being as compellingly plotted and emotionally resonant as it was, god bless peak tv&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jeffrey Moro (@jeffreymoro) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jeffreymoro/status/714505752950489089&quot;&gt;March 28, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;best show about fatherhood and also the virtues of staggeringly large doses of hallucinogenic substances we never deserved&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jeffrey Moro (@jeffreymoro) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jeffreymoro/status/714505999005122560&quot;&gt;March 28, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On the Virtues of Knockoffs, or, How to Make an Encrypted Journal on Your Computer</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/02/09/virtue-of-knockoffs/"/>
   <updated>2016-02-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2016/02/09/virtue-of-knockoffs</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I used to use a journal app called &lt;a href=&quot;http://dayoneapp.com&quot;&gt;Day One&lt;/a&gt;. It was a good enough app, given how infrequently I used it. It synced across my devices, it was a pleasing shade of start-up blue, and it was featured often enough in the App Store that I felt reasonably confident that it wasn’t going anywhere anytime soon. I put around four hundred entries in it over the course of three or so years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, Bloom Built, LLC, the company behind Day One, did a wholly sensible thing given the minimal margins and intense competition Selling Apps entails these days: they released a 2.0 update that was a separate app from the 1.0, with lavishly appointed new features and a substantially increased price. I purchased the original Day One app for $15 across OS X and iOS; 2.0 (setting aside an immediate 50% off sale to entice upgraders like myself) would set me back $50.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again: this was a wholly sensible thing for Bloom Built to do! It’s hard out there for immaterial economies dependent on a single virtual storefront run by a massive corporation that extracts rent in exchange for convenience and visibility. But two things struck me about this new 2.0 release: first, its substantial price increase, which alerted me also to the fact that a subsequent 3.0 would most likely cost me just as much if not more; and second, the persistent lack of encryption for my journal entries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because yes! This was a journal app that had lacked, despite persistent customer feedback, a reliable way to encrypt entries—entries which were stored in plain text and synchronized across your choice of cloud service. Well, your choice until 2.0: users are now locked in to using Bloom Built’s own proprietary synchronization service. I began to grow skeptical about my desire to pay $50 to put my thoughts and fears in plain text on a small start-up’s servers. I began to grow skeptical about continuing to use the (admittedly still perfectly functional) 1.0 iteration of the app. I (you see where this is going?) decided to buid myself a knockoff journal program, just for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;building-a-knockoff-journal-app-on-the-os-x-system-of-your-choice&quot;&gt;Building a Knockoff Journal App on the OS X System of Your Choice&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started by extracting all of my entries out of Day One. Thankfully (really, truly thankfully: many apps don’t bother with this at all [I’m looking at &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;, Evernote, with your weird HTML/XML export options]) it supports straightforward plain text export, so I manage to get all of my entries into a nice folder. I didn’t decide to write a post about this until after I’d already deleted Day One off of my computer, so just imagine that you’re looking at a screenshot of a folder filled with happy little text files, instead of this Vine of Jeff Goldblum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://vine.co/v/iJVhe0qUEHV/embed/simple&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://platform.vine.co/static/scripts/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll also skip over the painfully interminable finagling that it took to get all of the file names in a standardized order that would appear chronologically in my text editor of choice (&lt;a href=&quot;http://sublimetext.com&quot;&gt;Sublime Text&lt;/a&gt;, if you want to know where I stand on These Important Issues). Let’s just leave it at I am incredibly grateful for both the Automator app build into OS X and the fact that “Rename all…” is a secretly powerful right-click option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I had all of my old entries in a folder, ready to be a journal in and of their own right. If I didn’t have any secrets, I could just stop now! (This is the low-key powerful thing about computers: &lt;a href=&quot;https://al3x.net/2009/01/31/against-everything-buckets.html&quot;&gt;like half of the apps we have could probably be replaced by files in folders&lt;/a&gt;) But I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; have secrets, or at least, I &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; I have secrets, so I need some kind of encryption. Thankfully, OS X has a solution baked right in to its operating system!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/knockoff-1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Disk Utility&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good old Disk Utility. This is where you used to go when something was acting up on your computer and you needed to “Repair File Permissions” or some other voodoo that seemed to make things better but you were never sure how? It got nerfed a bit in the 10.11 El Capitan update, but the core functionality we need is still there, up in the File &amp;gt; New Image menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/knockoff-2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Command-N, for those in the know.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Disk Utility, I can create my own Disk Image file—the same images that we use when we install programs from not-the-App-Store—stick my files in it, and slap a password on it. You’ll see here that I’m choosing 256 bit AES encryption (I don’t know precisely what it means either! But 256 bits means more bits to choose from, which means more randomness, which means harder-to-crack, and that’s good enough for me) and a .sparsebundle image rather than .dmg. Why? A .dmg is one flat file, whereas a .sparsebundle is actually a collection of bands of files—this makes it easier to back up, because you only have to synchronize the bands that have changed, and also gives you a chance to recover part of the image if one of the bands fails, since the others would be, theoretically, unaffected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/knockoff-3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Much GUI, Wow&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there, I just put my .md files on the new disk image, and when I’m done writing, eject it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s not super user-friendly. I mean, none of this is &lt;em&gt;super&lt;/em&gt; user-friendly: that’s why we have apps like Day One. But I can still hack together some knockoff functionality with the help of some carefully chosen shell aliases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-shell&quot; data-lang=&quot;shell&quot;&gt;&lt;table style=&quot;border-spacing: 0&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter gl&quot; style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;alias &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;journal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'hdiutil attach /path/to/journal.sparsebundle; subl --project /Volumes/journal/journal.sublime-project'&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;alias &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;eject&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'hdiutil detach /Volumes/journal; rsync -avh /path/to/journal.sparsebundle /path/to/backuplocation'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this means is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-shell&quot; data-lang=&quot;shell&quot;&gt;&lt;table style=&quot;border-spacing: 0&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter gl&quot; style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;alias &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;journal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;when I type &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;journal&lt;/code&gt; in the command line application of my choice, it executes all of the following commands sequentially.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-shell&quot; data-lang=&quot;shell&quot;&gt;&lt;table style=&quot;border-spacing: 0&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter gl&quot; style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;hdiutil attach /path/to/journal.sparsebundle; &lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, mount my journal to my Desktop (this is the same as if I double-clicked it). The command line will prompt me for my password all on its own. I could also pass the password along with the initial command, but then that would entail putting my password in plain text on my computer, which, no?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-shell&quot; data-lang=&quot;shell&quot;&gt;&lt;table style=&quot;border-spacing: 0&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter gl&quot; style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;subl --project /Volumes/journal/journal.sublime-project &lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made a Sublime Text project that corresponds to my journal entries folder, giving me a GUI of sorts. This command pops that open automatically, saving me the extra clicks to open Sublime Text and load the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, when I type &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;eject&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-shell&quot; data-lang=&quot;shell&quot;&gt;&lt;table style=&quot;border-spacing: 0&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter gl&quot; style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;hdiutil detach /Volumes/journal; &lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I eject the .sparsebundle, and for kicks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-shell&quot; data-lang=&quot;shell&quot;&gt;&lt;table style=&quot;border-spacing: 0&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter gl&quot; style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;rsync -avh /path/to/journal.sparsebundle /path/to/backuplocation&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rsync&lt;/code&gt; to synchronize a copy to another location on my computer, in case something terrible happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s it! You have yourself a totally-jankety-but-still-pretty-functional-and-also-encrypted-unlike-with-other-apps-who-shall-remain-nameless journal app!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;all-the-good-shit-is-always-down-a-manhole&quot;&gt;“All the good shit is always down a manhole.”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/knockoff-4.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&quot;Jesus Christ.&quot;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While building my knockoff journal, I was reminded of John Herrmann’s endlessly compelling essay &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/matter/shitphone-a-love-story-a44e66434807#.pxei6ttto&quot;&gt;“Shitphone: A Love Story,”&lt;/a&gt; about his affinity for off-brand electronics. He writes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Off-brand electronics are, like their branded counterparts, interesting for a limited amount of time: The highest-end branded version of a product offers a chance to taste the luxurious future of technology; the shitworld version lets you preview a more practical future — the future most of the global electronics-buying public will actually enjoy. Take the Jambox, a small and dazzlingly expensive prism of speakers and battery and wireless radios that plays music from nearly any phone at a respectable volume; it was a sensation for a few years after its introduction in 2010. By 2013, off-brand speakers were making major inroads online, allowing shoppers like me to feel like we were somehow gaming the system….Off-brand electronics are alluring only when they feel like deals — that is, only as long as there are more popular branded alternatives which they can imply are overpriced. They’re interesting, in other words, for as long as they make the buyer feel smart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t precisely the same kind of knockoff I built: mine is more akin to Molly Ringwald piecing together her own prom dress in &lt;em&gt;Pretty in Pink&lt;/em&gt; than Herrmann’s shitphone. But the pleasures are similar: a feeling of global grift, of pulling something over on the electronic economy’s expectations for my purchasing habits. To deliberately embrace cheapness and shoddiness is a possible virtue in a time of clean, flat, minimal, and expensive design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In embracing knockoffs, I realized how many programs I use on a day-to-day basis—productivity, journaling, to-do-listing, messaging, even makings GIFs—are more or less GUIs plastered on top of basic functionalities baked into my operating system. Nine times out of ten, I was paying for convenience, not functionality. It was the rare program that added something genuinely new to my computer; most reorganized, made transparent (or opaque) various functions that already existed. Now: very often that convenience is what keeps me safe and sane, what lets me spend time doing &lt;em&gt;literally anything else with my life&lt;/em&gt; besides tinkering with my computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But sometimes you run up against a software that decides to make something opaque that you would prefer to be transparent, or reveals something about itself, its functionality, its politics, its economy that you would have rather stayed hidden. At that point, it’s down the manhole, where all the good shit really is.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A semi-comprehensive list of my obsessions circa January 17th, 2016</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/01/17/obsessions-circa-jan17/"/>
   <updated>2016-01-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2016/01/17/obsessions-circa-jan17</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the lacuna between the Smith and Amherst iterations of &lt;a href=&quot;http://ecomedia.jeffreymoro.com&quot;&gt;my Interterm course on media archaeology and climate change&lt;/a&gt;, a few things that have lodged themselves in my brainspace:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;david-bowies-blackstar&quot;&gt;David Bowie’s &lt;em&gt;Blackstar&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Something happened the day that he died /&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Spirit rose a meter and then stepped aside&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I listened through David Bowie’s final album on a plane from Seattle to Boston. I had downloaded it, laptop open, off of a sketchy public Wi-Fi signal, while standing in the Southwest queue to board the plane. I flew back the Sunday that he passed away, although none of us knew it yet. I found out in the middle of the night, after driving back home from Logan Airport: a chance glance at Twitter before going to bed. I spent five minutes in silence flipping between Twitter and my web browser while my partner unpacked our clothes in the other room, before bursting in and telling her, “David Bowie is dead.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a gorgeous and terrifying album. I’ve listened to it maybe shy of a dozen times this week. David was synthesizing and inventing new sounds right up until the end, and I love him for that. I’ve seen a number of articles breaking down all of the clues he left us—is “Blackstar” a reference to a cancer lesion? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h0Jkv1cs6PE&quot;&gt;this Elvis song?&lt;/a&gt; what does &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=y-JqH1M4Ya8&quot;&gt;the Lazarus video&lt;/a&gt; tell us?—but &lt;em&gt;Blackstar&lt;/em&gt;’s true genius is how it gives us an example to live by. It shows how we might face down death and say, “Yes. But not yet.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mubi&quot;&gt;MUBI&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few months ago I finally ponied up for a subscription to &lt;a href=&quot;http://mubi.com&quot;&gt;Mubi&lt;/a&gt;, a highly-curated streaming service for über film nerds. I love explaining its curation model to people: there are only ever thirty films on the service, and each day it loses one film and gains a new film. Its form interrogates what’s most frustrating about Netflix—the way that films will appear and disappear, more or less at random, given the expirations and vagaries of distribution contracts. When one adds in the fact that there’s practically never anything (apart from television shows) that I really &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to watch on Netflix, the fact that I can log in to Mubi and find at least one film that’s interesting, that I wouldn’t have known about or be able to track down otherwise, is a small gift. So far I’ve watched a documentary about Indian and Israeli musicians collaborating on an album (&lt;em&gt;Junun&lt;/em&gt;), a film about a grandfatherly CIA agent messing with the bureaucracy that fired him (&lt;em&gt;Hopscotch&lt;/em&gt;), a dumb-as-rocks Marx Brothers movie (&lt;em&gt;A Night in Casablanca&lt;/em&gt;), and an over-caffeinated and hyper-inventive French stop-motion-animated film (&lt;em&gt;A Town Called Panic&lt;/em&gt;), among others. Strong endorse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;electronic-waste-and-whether-or-not-i-should-upgrade-my-phone&quot;&gt;Electronic Waste and Whether or Not I Should Upgrade My Phone&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I wrote in the lede, I’m teaching &lt;a href=&quot;http://ecomedia.jeffreymoro.com&quot;&gt;a class&lt;/a&gt; about electronic waste, climate change, and how the humanities can tackle ideas of apocalypse. (It’s been surprisingly cheery to teach in the dead of winter! Although I think my students have gotten a little bummed out: one said this past week, “I’m glad that we’re talking about these questions, because they’ve demonstrated for me how much I go out of my way to ignore them.”) One of the struggles I’m facing, though, is more prosaic than hyperobjects, media archaeology, and the Anthropocene: I’m due for a phone upgrade. Can I ethically upgrade my phone?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The straightforward answer is “No, not really.” As Jussi Parikka’s excellent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.upress.umn.edu/book-division/books/a-geology-of-media&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Geology of Media&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; discusses, it’s more or less impossible to find any computational artifacts that haven’t touched some conflict-ridden region, or that don’t contribute to broad cycles of pollution and waste. Even the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fairphone.com&quot;&gt;Fairphone&lt;/a&gt;, a new smartphone designed with ethics in mind, can only reliably guarantee that two metals in it are conflict-free—to say nothing of the by-products of the manufacturing process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s also the issue of the broader smartphone upgrade cycle. I was able to get my current phone (an iPhone 5C) heavily discounted: it was nearing obsolescence at the time and AT&amp;amp;T still offered carrier subsidies. Now, my choices are either to lock myself into an installment plan predicated on a desire to upgrade my phone as frequently as possible, simultaneously contributing at twice my current rate to the production and consumption of electronic waste &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; obviating any claim I have to actually &lt;em&gt;owning&lt;/em&gt; the phone (we had a great conversation in class last week about how Apple no longer sells you an iPhone, they sell you the Platonic &lt;em&gt;concept&lt;/em&gt; of an iPhone, and lease out various manifestations of that concept), &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; to pay the full sticker price for the phone, assuming I want to stay with Apple. I don’t object in principle, but I’ll let you estimate exactly how much cash Mellon forks out for my salary!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’ve spent the last week going down research rabbit holes. Do I stay with Apple? Switch to Android? Switch to Android but specifically target a budget phone—one that may not actually last any longer than two years and is just as un-upgradeable as the iPhone? I’ve realized what I really want is a modular, upgradeable smartphone chassis, à la &lt;a href=&quot;https://phonebloks.com&quot;&gt;Phonebloks&lt;/a&gt;, a proof-of-concept that a student pointed me towards last week. Such a phone (which Google has ostensibly picked up in its &lt;a href=&quot;http://projectara.com&quot;&gt;Project Ara&lt;/a&gt;) would make it easy to keep the same phone and repair, replace, and upgrade a patchwork of components—saving me money and reducing e-waste. However, it doesn’t look like such a product is more than a concept right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So honestly? My little 5C is chugging along great, and I don’t ask much of it besides to get me on Twitter and play my music (don’t even get me &lt;em&gt;started&lt;/em&gt; on the travesty that is Apple turfing the iPod Classic). I’ll probably hang onto it for the foreseeable future—although I’m glad to have spent the time digging into sustainable, modular futures.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On electronic literature, Internet art, and digital galleries</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/10/23/announcing-elit-netart/"/>
   <updated>2015-10-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2015/10/23/announcing-elit-netart</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Over the past few months, I’ve been working on and off on &lt;a href=&quot;http://elit.jeffreymoro.com&quot;&gt;elit.jeffreymoro.com&lt;/a&gt;, the digital home and instantiation of my &lt;em&gt;E.LIT / NET.ART&lt;/em&gt; project. And now, after doubling down on the work over the past month, I’m excited to launch it as a useable resource.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;1px&quot; src=&quot;/assets/img/elit-site-1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Look, ma, I made a website!&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;E.LIT / NET.ART&lt;/em&gt; is a loose conglomeration of mini curation projects around electronic literature, Internet art, and digitally-inflected cinema.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The project started as a series of pop-up IRL galleries across the Five Colleges of Western Massachusetts; I collaborated with libraries to take up residency in spare rooms and computer labs for a day or two and run a weird assortment of e-lit pieces from 1975 to now, with the aim of giving undergrads (and staff and faculty, for that matter) an opportunity to see digital art in the wild, so to speak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://elit.jeffreymoro.com&quot;&gt;https://elit.jeffreymoro.com&lt;/a&gt; also hosts information about the course that I taught in January of 2015 on many of the pieces that were in the original gallery series. I’ve gone ahead and put up my &lt;a href=&quot;http://elit.jeffreymoro.com/course&quot;&gt;syllabus&lt;/a&gt; as well, in the hopes that it’s useful as a starting point for anyone looking to learn more about electronic literature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;1px&quot; src=&quot;/assets/img/elit-site-2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site is (like all sites these days) a continual work-in-progress: rather than continue to host IRL galleries, I’m shifting much of my curatorial energies to this online version of the installation, although it’s certainly not outside the realm of possibility that I put up &lt;em&gt;E.LIT / NET.ART 2.0&lt;/em&gt; in the coming months. In particular, I’m still working on putting together captions for the pieces in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://elit.jeffreymoro.com/screening&quot;&gt;screening&lt;/a&gt; section of the site, and fleshing out the captions for all pieces now that I’m not constrained by a four-by-six inch card. And—I’ve hidden away a couple of easter eggs throughout the site, particularly in the faux-command-line that I’m alternately proud of and exasperated with. Let me know what you find!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;This is a clunky term, to be sure, but I’ve been toying with it in order to distinguish cinema in which the &lt;em&gt;format&lt;/em&gt; is materially digital (i.e., video rather than celluloid) and cinema that takes up digital aesthetics and politics. Which is not to say that material format isn’t imbricated with those questions—but there’s a broader history of digital cinema before video.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>&ldquo;The end of the world has already occurred...&rdquo;</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/10/15/the-end-of-the-world/"/>
   <updated>2015-10-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2015/10/15/the-end-of-the-world</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The end of the world has already occurred,” writes philosopher Timothy Morton in &lt;em&gt;Hyperobjects&lt;/em&gt;, his investigation of media theory and climate change. In this claim, Morton synthesizes contemporary anxieties around the ongoing tenability of industrial capitalism and the fractured relationships between technology, climate, and humankind. This week-long course takes Morton’s ideas as a starting point for exploring the media history, materiality, and infrastructures of digital and network technologies, and interrogates how the digital humanities and media studies might theorize and respond practically to climate upheaval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timothy Morton makes a second appearance on my blog as I put together my new week-long course &lt;em&gt;Media Archaeology, Climate Change, &amp;amp; the Digital (Non)humanities&lt;/em&gt;, which I’ll teach this January at Smith and Amherst Colleges. &lt;a href=&quot;http://ecomedia.5colldh.org&quot;&gt;Go take a look at the course website&lt;/a&gt; and register if you’re interested in spending a week with me talking about the future of the digital humanities and &lt;em&gt;literal&lt;/em&gt; garbage!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On yard sales</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/09/28/on-yardsales/"/>
   <updated>2015-09-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2015/09/28/on-yardsales</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You will advertise the yard sale as starting at 9:00 AM. You will plan your days leading up to the yard sale blissfully ensconced in the absolute fixity of that reality; you will distribute printed matter, set alarms, make previous-night-drinking decisions based upon the assumed reality that you will begin selling your shit at 9:00 AM. This is, in fact, a lie. A lie you tell yourself so that you may feel that the world, your world, is somehow regular, explainable, controllable. The yard sale begins when the first old man in a hatchback rolls up and knocks on your apartment building’s door. This will be at 7:15 AM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you interested in the affective experience of selling your garbage on the street? &lt;a href=&quot;http://detritus.website/words/concepts/yardsale/&quot;&gt;Boy, did I write something for you.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A semi-comprehensive list of my obsessions circa September 27th, 2015</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/09/27/obsessions-circa-sept27/"/>
   <updated>2015-09-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2015/09/27/obsessions-circa-sept27</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to a semi-regular feature in which I list the things that are sticking in my head, that I can’t seem to shake, and that I’m not even trying to shake because I love them so much. (Why yes, this &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a post that’s at least glancingly about &lt;em&gt;Hamilton&lt;/em&gt;.) To wit:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;elena-ferrantes-neapolitan-novels&quot;&gt;Elena Ferrante’s &lt;em&gt;Neapolitan Novels&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s hard to say what Pasquale’s answers did to Lila. I’m in danger of getting it wrong, partly because on me, at the time, they had no concrete effect. But she, in her usual way, was moved and altered by them, so that for the entire summer she tormented me with a single concept that I found quite unbearable. I’ll try to summarize it, using the language of today, like this: there are no gestures, words, or sighs that do not containt the sum of all the crimes that human beings have committed and commit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I may be late to the party here, Ferrante’s novels are a thunderstrike, all rage and passion and carefully modulated blows to the heart. I can’t &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; talk about them, rave about them to everyone I know. I am a Ferrante stan, through and through. I burned through &lt;em&gt;My Brilliant Friend&lt;/em&gt; (that quote is from page 153) and am deliberately staving off starting &lt;em&gt;The Story of a New Name&lt;/em&gt; so that I don’t rack up an immense bill at my local bookstore. (I’m distracting myself with Bulgakov’s &lt;em&gt;The Master and Margarita&lt;/em&gt;, but as this is a post about my obsessions, there you go.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hamilton&quot;&gt;Hamilton&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The only way to survive in the aftermath of the monoculture, when everyone is famous not for 15 minutes but to 15 people, is to be, earnestly and unmistakably, yourself. People now are constantly curating our own constellations of personal stars, never mind what MTV has to suggest. If you are 100 people’s ninth favorite thing, to borrow a phrase from another musical, you will not survive. The ones who make it are the ones who are nine people’s favorite thing.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Be yourself, in all your glorious weirdness, with all the risk of looking stupid that entails.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If you worry about looking stupid, you will never find your people. If you waste time not making the one thing you would die if you didn’t make, you will die all the same. Life is too short not to be yourself — especially if yourself is Alexander Hamilton. Yes, that sentiment is probably available as an awful driftwood plaque at Anthropologie, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/compost/wp/2015/09/21/hamilton-and-the-end-of-irony/&quot;&gt;but that doesn’t make it less true.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m binging on the zeitgeist. Like the vast majority of people in this world who do not live in New York City, I have experienced &lt;em&gt;Hamilton&lt;/em&gt; by proxy, through rapturous reviews, breathless tweets, and that soundtrack, that glorious, lengthy, electric soundtrack. I generally try to resist hype, especially when the hype surrounds a thing so localized and specialized that most people have no hope of ever experiencing it. But I’m three rotations in to the soundtrack and I have to give in: I purchased tickets for next July (Broadway’s a racket, huh?) earlier tonight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;vermont-cheddar-mashed-potatoes&quot;&gt;Vermont Cheddar Mashed Potatoes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Early American colonists may not have eaten Cheddar at the first Thanksgiving, but they certainly began to make it in the traditional English manner soon thereafter. At some point the colonies were actually exporting domestic cheese to the mother country, where it was known as Yankee Cheddar.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;To some, Cheddar is synonymous with Vermont, even if it is produced in several other states, too. For most, mashed potatoes are an absolute essential for a proper Thanksgiving table. Combining them seems natural, whether customary or not. Using two-year-old aged Vermont Cheddar, which is deeply flavored but not too sharp, gives these creamy mashed potatoes a subtle Cheddar presence, &lt;a href=&quot;http://cooking.nytimes.com/recipes/1016914-vermont-cheddar-mashed-potatoes&quot;&gt;neither overwhelmingly cheesy nor gooey.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made these for dinner tonight, with barbecue tempeh and green beans, and I can only stop myself from continuing to eat them by making meticulous plans to fry them up as potato cakes for breakfast tomorrow morning. 10/10, would mash potatoes again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dragon-quest-v&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dragon Quest V&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No quotes, no articles, there’s nothing zeitgeist-y about this one. The &lt;em&gt;Dragon Quest&lt;/em&gt; series, in their warm regularity, are the mashed potatoes of video games: comforting, familiar, but still ripe for variation, capable of a charming twist of surprise. They’re a reminder that not everything has to disrupt, not all things have to shock and awe. I’ve been replaying the fifth game in the series, which follows our protagonist from birth to adulthood, through childhood games, striking loss, marriage, and fatherhood with surprising deftness. Has it aged poorly in places? Certainly. Is its aggressive heteronormativity grating? Of course. But, like mashed potatoes, sometimes one gets a craving for something straightforward, done with care.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On Memory Editing, Glitches, and Play</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/09/16/on-picture-processing-and-memory-editing/"/>
   <updated>2015-09-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2015/09/16/on-picture-processing-and-memory-editing</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/ppu-1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Stills from &lt;a href=&quot;http://ohsqueezy.itch.io/ppu&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Picture Processing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks ago, an &lt;a href=&quot;http://ohsqueezy.itch.io&quot;&gt;independent game maker&lt;/a&gt; put out a game called &lt;a href=&quot;http://ohsqueezy.itch.io/ppu&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Picture Processing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, in which you, the player, telepathically commune with a broken NES console and manipulate the system’s memory values to repair error-ridden, glitched-out game screens. (It’s going to get weirder from here on out, y’all, trust me.) Given that this is &lt;em&gt;highly relevant&lt;/em&gt; to a number of my interests, I wanted to put a few words down here about the experience of playing this game and the role of memory editing in video games and digital media as related to play. As I wrote &lt;a href=&quot;http://codex.thecritical.is/strange-creatures/&quot;&gt;in a short meditation&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hastac2015.org/schedule/&quot;&gt;2015’s HASTAC conference&lt;/a&gt;, I’m interested in excavating moments in which the technical apparatus and mathematical underpinning of video games become sites of play beyond the terrain envisioned by the game’s designers. That digital technologies are themselves sites of potential play is uncontroversial: ask any artist, or mathematician, or tinkerer. &lt;em&gt;Picture Processing&lt;/em&gt; gives us something different, a glimpse at a kind of unsanctioned play that takes as its subject the apparatus itself. It’s the exploration of the apparatus that interests me, and the ways in which play becomes a tool for re-envisioning our relationships (should they ever be bifurcated?) to software and hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At its core, &lt;em&gt;Picture Processing&lt;/em&gt; is a tile-swapping puzzle game, not dissimilar to the physical 3-by-3-picture-grid-with-one-piece-missing games I played in dentists’ offices throughout my youth. In each level, the player swaps individual 8-bit tiles through up to sixteen hexadecimal memory locations until the original game screen is descrambled and “revealed.” &lt;em&gt;Picture Processing&lt;/em&gt; distinguishes itself from other puzzle games through its strategic use of metaphor and abstraction. Rather than manipulate the NES’s picture processing unit (the chip through which the console draws images to a television screen, and the game’s namesake) through assembly code or fiddling with voltages, the game posits the play “meditating” so that psychic “manipulation of the system’s PPU” will be “granted.” Only through a direct “telepathic” link between mind and machine can the player reorganize the broken, glitched game screens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/ppu-2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Loading a new &lt;em&gt;Picture Processing&lt;/em&gt; game.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Picture Processing&lt;/em&gt;’s psychic metaphors are a far cry from the usual way that players access and manipulate a game’s encoded memory—and the game’s goal of restoring broken screens contrasts players’ general motivations. When I was young, in the days before sophisticated digital rights protection technologies, one could buy one of a range of cheat-code devices from any store that sold video games. These devices, which went by names like “Gameshark,” “Game Genie,” or “Action Replay,” served as an intermediary between console and cartridge, and provided the player an interface through which to directly access and manipulate the active flow of data. Most of the time, players used these to beat the system: most of the devices came preloaded with pieces of code that would provide infinite lives, mitigate damage, or skip through difficult levels for many games on the market. Some devices, like one that I had for the Game Boy, had a button on the device itself that could call up a memory editor during active play. Players could come to a certain part in the game, bring up a memory editor, mess around with some hexadecimal values, and return to play, with any number of desired (and, if one wasn’t careful, &lt;em&gt;undesired&lt;/em&gt;) effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/ppu-3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Various kinds of cheat devices.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote about these device’s affective relationship to play and gameworlds in that past essay I wrote for HASTAC, &lt;a href=&quot;http://codex.thecritical.is/strange-creatures/&quot;&gt;“Strange Creatures Made of Memory.”&lt;/a&gt; Rather than plagiarize myself, I’ll just quote a section:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Glitches and cheat codes are a violent literacy, a writing an dreading that quite literally destabilizes the text, often to the point of crash and failure. At the same time, they point to a hidden vitality running through each zero and one, and a capacity, if given the right conditions, for the game itself, an agglomeration of software and hardware, to assert a strange life as often as a sudden death. How can we characterize this vitality?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Picture Processing&lt;/em&gt; stands in contrast to the Gameshark: rather than break a game apart so that I can cheat my way to the top or explore the strange possibilities of brokenness, &lt;em&gt;Picture Processing&lt;/em&gt; asks us to delve into a game’s code and set right what entropy has made chaos. I can’t help but notice, though, that &lt;em&gt;Picture Processing&lt;/em&gt;’s relationship to play and work is skewed. The game purports to put us in communion with the technology, plugged in à la &lt;em&gt;Neuromancer&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;The Matrix&lt;/em&gt;. The game’s textual and paratexual metaphors—“meditating,” “telepathically accessing”—all point to a transhumanist melding of mind and machine. Still, the game’s work is prosaic. Switch tilesets around until you get to the correct arrangement, after which the game rewards you with another screen to rearrange. The work is repetitive, even tedious. One can imagine that it’s the precise kind of work that would be better accomplished by machine, given that the game is conceptually winnable by running through each possible programmatic permutation of hexadecimal variables. &lt;em&gt;Picture Processing&lt;/em&gt; models the labor of a play tester—or maybe just the machine itself?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other thread I want to follow here is that of play. When I was a child, messing around with Gamesharks wasn’t just a way of by-passing difficult levels, it was a way to extend the game’s universe past the boundaries envisioned by game designers. The Gameshark was, in its own strange way, my first experience with what we might now term digital “open-world play”: exploring a non-linear, non-task-oriented digital space with no objective other than to see what I could see, and to make the game crash in new and interesting ways. Looking back, it was also my first experinece with rudimentary computer programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine has two children: one just into double digits, and one who’s recently graduated into full sentences. She has made a deliberate parenting choice to surround both her children with toys and technologies that both stimulate their creativity and instruct on the increasingly computational and programmatic nature of the contemporary world. I marvel at some of these toys, at their sophistication, their elegance, the extent to which they take complex concepts such as iteration, variability, and programmed architecture and distill them into drag-and-drop shapes and accessible metaphor. I point to these toys not to draw some kind of differential between my friend’s children’s childhood and my own—we’re separated by twenty years, yes, but my childhood was firmly in an age of pervasive digital technology—but to think through the ways that we’ve decided, over the past twenty or thirty years, to give some of our most interesting and accessible technologies for engaging with the capital-D Digital to children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Picture Processing&lt;/em&gt; is a fun game, don’t get me wrong! I enjoy how it foregrounds things that other games keep hidden: the technological apparatus churning underneath. I just think I might have had even more fun with it if it weren’t leading me somewhere, if it weren’t trying to tell me what to do. If it didn’t ask me to return a game to normal (i.e., to what was written, to what was coded, to what looks reasonable, accessible, natural), but instead opened up a space of confusion, disaster, malleability. After all, it’s only a game, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The deeply nerdy among you might be interested in learning more about the original NES Picture Processing Unit, and would be please to know that there is a small-but-lively NES dev scene on this great Internet of ours. You can find a full technical breakdown of the PPU-as-apparatus &lt;a href=&quot;http://nesdev.com/2C02%20technical%20reference.TXT&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and Wikipedia has a surprisingly thorough generalist look at the PPU &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Picture_Processing_Unit&quot;&gt;over here&lt;/a&gt;. I’m planning on writing more about the PPU, particularly its relationship to, as Alexander Galloway writes in&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.upress.umn.edu/book-division/books/gaming&quot;&gt;Gaming: Essays on Algorithmic Culture&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;its relationship to a set of “machinic embodiments”: ways that the apparatus makes itself known, “emanat[ing] outward,” or “math made visible” (32).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>&ldquo;These gigantic timescales are truly humiliating...&rdquo;</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/09/13/these-gigantic-timescales/"/>
   <updated>2015-09-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2015/09/13/these-gigantic-timescales</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;These gigantic timescales are truly humiliating in the sense that they force us to realize how close to Earth we are. Infinity is far easier to cope with. Infinity brings to mind our cognitive powers, which is why for Kant the mathematical sublime is the realization that infinity is an uncountably vast magnitude beyond magnitude. But hyperobjects are not forever. What they offer instead is very large finitude. I can think infinity. But I can’t count up to one hundred thousand. I have written one hundred thousand words, in fits and starts. But one hundred thousand years? It’s unimaginably vast. Yet there it is, staring me in the face, as the hyperobject global warming. And I helped cause it. I am directly responsible for beings that far into the future, insofar as two things will be true simultaneously: no one then will meaningfully be related to me; and my smallest action now will affect that time in profound ways. A Styrofoam cup will outlive me by over four hundred years. The plastic bag in Ramin Bahrani’s movie (in the voice of Werner Herzog) wishes to talk to the woman it knows as its maker, the woman who used it to carry her groceries: “If I could meet my maker, I would tell her just one thing: I wish that she had created me so that I could die.” To hear a plastic bag wish such a thing is profoundly different from thinking abstract infinity. There is a real sense in which it is far easier to conceive of “forever” than very large finitude. Forever makes you feel important. One hundred thousand years makes you wonder whether you can imagine one hundred thousand anything. It seems rather abstract to imagine that a book is one hundred thousand words long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading Timothy Morton’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.upress.umn.edu/book-division/books/hyperobjects&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hyperobjects: Philosophy and Ecology After the End of the World&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (University of Minnestota Press, 2013, this quote from pg. 60) is the closest I’ve gotten in a while to feeling like I’m in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kSnJl7B_TVs&amp;amp;noredirect=1&quot;&gt;Total Perspective Vortex&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On seeing through Twitter</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/09/02/on-seeing-through-Twitter/"/>
   <updated>2015-09-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2015/09/02/on-seeing-through-Twitter</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On August 24th, Ars Technica reported that Twitter (the corporation) cut off API access to Twitter (the database) for a number of websites. These websites, &lt;a href=&quot;http://politwoops.sunlightfoundation.com&quot;&gt;Politwoops&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://diplotwoops.org&quot;&gt;Diplotwoops&lt;/a&gt;, were dedicated to archiving and displaying tweets that the official accounts of politicians, diplomats, and other governmental agencies tweeted and then deleted. &lt;a href=&quot;http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2015/08/twitter-cuts-api-access-to-more-sites-archiving-deleted-politicians-tweets/&quot;&gt;From Ars’ article&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Twitter has severed API access to more sites that archive deleted tweets from politicians. The most recent targets—Diplotwoops and the international version of Politwoops—spanned at least 30 countries, but Twitter found the sites to be in breach of the service’s privacy policy.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This weekend’s development comes three months after Twitter cut API access for the US’ political tweet watchdog, Politwoops, for the same reason. The Sunlight Foundation ran the US Politwoops, and the Open State Foundation ran 30 international versions of Politwoops in addition to Diplotwoops. Both organizations lashed out at this recent decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For sites like Diplotwoops and Politwoops, API access is everything. An API (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Application_programming_interface&quot;&gt;application programming interface&lt;/a&gt;) is a kind of grammar, a set of instructions for interacting with a computing platform. The Twitter API and the permissions granted through its use were what powered these sites’ ability to access politicians’ live feeds, write tweets to a database, check for later deletions, and then post those deleted tweets to the public Internet. Twitter’s stated reason for shutting these services down was that they were in violation of the API’s terms of use, which &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.twitter.com/overview/terms/agreement-and-policy#3.Update_Respect_Users_Control_and_Privacy&quot;&gt;states that developers must&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;b. Take all reasonable efforts to do the following, provided that when requested by Twitter, you must promptly take such actions:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;i. Delete Content that Twitter reports as deleted or expired;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;ii. Change treatment of Content that Twitter reports is subject to changed sharing options (e.g., become protected); and&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;iii. Modify Content that Twitter reports has been modified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A straightforward enough case, right? However, as the Sunlight Foundation, the NGO that ran Politwoops, wrote on its blog when its API access was suspended, Twitter had contacted them about terms of use violations way back in 2012 and had reached an agreement with the Foundation to allow its website to operate unencumbered. &lt;a href=&quot;http://sunlightfoundation.com/blog/2015/06/04/eulogy-for-politwoops/&quot;&gt;To wit&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Days after Politwoops launched in 2012, Twitter contacted the Sunlight Foundation and told us, “Your service violates our API Terms of Service on a fundamental level.” We explained the goals of the project and agreed to create a human curation workflow to ensure that the site screened out corrected low-value tweets like typos, links and Twitter handles. We implemented this layer of journalistic judgment with blessings from Twitter and the site continued.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What changed between 2012 and 2015? There’s a feeling online, one that I’ve noticed in a number of channels but principally on Twitter, that something has changed, and not for the better. There’s a sense that surveillance, already a major part of our lives online, has expanded. There’s a sense of futility in the face of the “sharing economy,” as the trends instituted by comically evil corporations like Uber lock more of us in &lt;a href=&quot;http://platformcoop.net&quot;&gt;part-time, contingent labor&lt;/a&gt;. There’s a sense that social media has fulfilled its dark promise as &lt;a href=&quot;http://the-toast.net/2015/07/23/an-interview-with-sarah-jeong/&quot;&gt;a perfect tool for harassment&lt;/a&gt;, and women, people of color, people who speak up against the flow of garbage find themselves attacked and driven into protected accounts—or offline entirely. And there’s a sense that the Internet’s ability to amplify horrid events, to mobilize social activist movements like Arab Spring or Black Lives Matter, has a darker side: one that reifies and insists on witnessing trauma and injustice beyond a human’s capacity to withstand it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What changed between 2012 and 2015? Trayvon Martin was murdered, Michael Brown was murdered, Renisha McBride was murdered. We had an election, are about to have another one. Twitter gained hundreds of thousands of users, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2015/08/twitter-global-social-media/402415/&quot;&gt;but they’re not talking&lt;/a&gt;. And the money gathers upward, like it always has. Our lives online feel increasingly mandatory, and increasingly exhausting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watching Twitter (the corporation) pull the plug on sites like Diplotwoops and Politwoops teaches us what power is when social media networks are concerned. I want to use their example to kick off what I anticipate will be a series of blog posts about Twitter, our utterances on it, and our relationships to each other through it. I agree with those who think that the Internet, as we know and knew it, is at some kind of breaking point. Let’s dig through the rubble together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past month, I’ve been collaborating with Marisa Parham on the beginnings of a project called &lt;em&gt;Still Life in Digital: Black Life, Trauma, and Social Media&lt;/em&gt;. The project’s goal, as we envision it, is to push on the rhetoric of the digital making things, relationships, utterances, and lives floaty, disembodied, cloud-like. For Black life, we argue, it does the opposite. Social media overconcretizes lives in ways that bodies can’t sustain. Web Smith writes about this in a Medium post called &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@web/our-truth-is-why-twitter-is-struggling-ffc6a4e02bcd&quot;&gt;“Our Truth is Why Twitter is Struggling,”&lt;/a&gt; in which he says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Twitter is suffering because it is the most accurate reflection of American society today. It’s not just what’s tweeted, it’s what isn’t tweeted. &lt;strong&gt;Each day, a new hashtag represents a dead child.&lt;/strong&gt; Often, there is a filmed murder attached. Often still, we watch it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[…]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dare I say, that Twitter’s problem is its ability to trigger us.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Every death reminds us that, even if we’re perfect, we may die today. Every advocacy of an African lion reminds us that African-Americans are traditionally less important than animals. We watch what’s important to our friends and then ask, why is my friendship not important to you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, we’ve been thinking about data visualization: how the graph, map, tree, or chart has gained prominence in the way we talk, write, and share online, and its role in making violence towards Black life constantly visible and explicable in ways that are both necessary and deleterious. It’s been my job over the past month to learn more about techniques for data visualization, how to turn corpuses of data, especially tweets, into compelling visual representations, and to think about what that process of representation entails. Our starting point was this striking heat map of tweets sent out during the week following Michael Brown’s shooting in Ferguson, MO:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;520&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://srogers.cartodb.com/viz/4a5eb582-23ed-11e4-bd6b-0e230854a1cb/embed_map&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; oallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; msallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are we seeing here? How are individual utterances, and the bodies that produced them, represented in a map like this? What &lt;em&gt;aren’t&lt;/em&gt; we seeing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I quickly became obsessed with the data underneath, with understanding how someone would go about accessing the raw stream of tweets and metadata that powers this or any other visualization. To begin collect tweets for our project, I used the same free, open, public API that powered Diplotwoops and Politwoops. I have to admit, I was a little shocked at what I saw constituted a single tweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s one tweet—one of mine, taken from a few days ago:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-json&quot; data-lang=&quot;json&quot;&gt;&lt;table style=&quot;border-spacing: 0&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter gl&quot; style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8
9
10
11
12
13
14
15
16
17
18
19
20
21
22
23
24
25
26
27
28
29
30
31
32
33
34
35
36
37
38
39
40
41
42
43
44
45
46
47
48
49
50
51
52
53
54
55
56
57
58
59
60
61
62
63
64
65
66
67
68
69
70
71
72
73
74
75
76
77
78
79
80
81
82
83
84
85
86
87
88
89
90&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;contributors&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;truncated&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;text&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;interesting reflection on who's doing the talking and the listening and the ignoring on this website dot com: http://t.co/RVzTR7pDGM&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;is_quote_status&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;in_reply_to_status_id&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;id&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;636912109163520000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;favorite_count&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;source&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&amp;lt;a href=\&quot;http://twitter.com\&quot; rel=\&quot;nofollow\&quot;&amp;gt;Twitter Web Client&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;retweeted&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;coordinates&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;entities&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;symbols&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[],&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;user_mentions&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[],&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;hashtags&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[],&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;urls&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;url&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;http://t.co/RVzTR7pDGM&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
            &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;indices&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;110&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;132&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;],&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
            &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;expanded_url&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;http://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2015/08/twitter-global-social-media/402415/&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;display_url&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;theatlantic.com/international/\u2026&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;},&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;in_reply_to_screen_name&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;in_reply_to_user_id&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;retweet_count&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;id_str&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;636912109163520000&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;favorited&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;user&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;follow_request_sent&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;has_extended_profile&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;profile_use_background_image&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;default_profile_image&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;id&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1478357942&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;profile_background_image_url_https&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;https://abs.twimg.com/images/themes/theme1/bg.png&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;verified&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;profile_text_color&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;333333&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;profile_image_url_https&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;https://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/611518361206423552/ICDpOPuK_normal.jpg&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;profile_sidebar_fill_color&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;DDEEF6&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;entities&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;url&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
                &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;urls&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;url&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;http://t.co/UuZFn8Zbva&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
                    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;indices&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;22&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;],&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
                    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;expanded_url&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;http://jeffreymoro.com&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
                    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;display_url&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;jeffreymoro.com&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;},&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
                &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;description&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;urls&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[]}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;},&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;followers_count&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;173&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;profile_sidebar_border_color&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;C0DEED&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;id_str&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;1478357942&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;profile_background_color&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;C0DEED&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;listed_count&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;17&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;is_translation_enabled&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;utc_offset&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;10800&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;statuses_count&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1636&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;description&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;electronic literature, media history, software studies // all-purpose post-bac for @5collDH // helps run @thecriticalis&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;friends_count&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;426&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;location&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Northampton, MA&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;profile_link_color&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;0084B4&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;profile_image_url&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;http://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/611518361206423552/ICDpOPuK_normal.jpg&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;following&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;geo_enabled&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;profile_banner_url&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;https://pbs.twimg.com/profile_banners/1478357942/1436916421&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;profile_background_image_url&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;http://abs.twimg.com/images/themes/theme1/bg.png&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;screen_name&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;jeffreymoro&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;lang&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;en&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;profile_background_tile&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;favourites_count&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;405&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;name&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Jeffrey Moro&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;notifications&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;url&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;http://t.co/UuZFn8Zbva&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;created_at&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Sun Jun 02 22:34:06 +0000 2013&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;contributors_enabled&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;time_zone&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Athens&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;protected&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;default_profile&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;is_translator&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;},&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;geo&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;in_reply_to_user_id_str&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;possibly_sensitive&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;lang&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;en&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;created_at&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Thu Aug 27 14:44:14 +0000 2015&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;in_reply_to_status_id_str&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;place&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;metadata&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;iso_language_code&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;en&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;result_type&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;recent&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s overwhelming. It feels like &lt;a href=&quot;http://westwing.wikia.com/wiki/Take_Out_the_Trash_Day&quot;&gt;that episode of &lt;em&gt;The West Wing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; when, to bamboozle reporters who ask for internal documents from the President’s office, the Bartlet administration releases &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt;, drowning the press in paper. This 90-line .json is a single tweet. Try working with more than &lt;a href=&quot;http://inkdroid.org/2014/08/30/a-ferguson-twitter-archive/&quot;&gt;13 million of them&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of these fields are self-explanatory, and after the initial shock dies down, make perfect sense from an architectural standpoint. The tweet’s text, its favorite count, whether it’s even been retweeted, geographic information: if you look at this document from the perspective of someone building a Twitter app, then everything becomes clear. I’m particularly interested in the “entities” field, which contains detailed information about all of the links &lt;em&gt;within&lt;/em&gt; a single tweet. One tweet effectively contains the full metadata for all of its relationships, which allows one to map out webs of fractal connections. (If you’re getting a weird &lt;em&gt;Neuromancer&lt;/em&gt;-y whiff from all of this, I don’t think it’s unintentional.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at these streams of data, I realized that visualization is more than charts and graphs. Twitter, the web interface, is itself a visualization, in the sense that it’s a representation in dimensional space of a complex dataset. Twitter, the web interface, relies on visual rhetoric to communication information and produce effects in the same way any well-made chart would. It’s useful to distinguish Twitter-the-interface from Twitter-the-data (and also from Twitter-the-corporation). Doing so allows us to understand (and here the software engineers are perhaps a step ahead of the academics, in the sense that the former has a rich vocabulary of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_as_a_service&quot;&gt;software/platform-as-a-service&lt;/a&gt; to understand this separation) what Twitter is doing when it pulls the plug on Politwoops or Diplotwoops: it’s implicitly claiming the value of one kind of visualization over another. The dataset is the same; it’s how you look at it that changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our lives online are subject to a regime of sight, of web sites and services that use design techniques to surface information in specific ways. When Web Smith writes that Twitter’s problem is “its ability to trigger us,” this is what he means. We’re given things to see, and little control over how we see them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I wrote above, I imagine this post is the first in an intermittent series over the next few months, exploring visualizations that I end up making for this project, and digging deeper into questions of how lives and bodies, particularly Black lives and Black bodies, are construed online. If you’re interested in learning more about how the Twitter API works (I am so far from an expert that it’s comical I’m even writing this blog post), there’s ample documentation at &lt;a href=&quot;http://dev.twitter.com&quot;&gt;dev.twitter.com&lt;/a&gt;. I recommend going and looking at that site in any case, particularly if you’re a regular Twitter user. It’s useful to see how the services that we use construe themselves on the backend, especially when they diverge radically from how they’d like us to perceive their front-ends. It’ll also give you a sense of how you might go about harvesting tweets for your own use (man, these metaphors get creepy &lt;em&gt;fast&lt;/em&gt;), though I hope to write about those processes more soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Visualizing the New Rigor</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/08/26/visualizing-the-new-rigor/"/>
   <updated>2015-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2015/08/26/visualizing-the-new-rigor</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Back in May, Five College Digital Humanities organized a conference called &lt;em&gt;The New Rigor&lt;/em&gt;, in which we tackled the question of what kinds of support and evaluation structures would best facilitate making interesting, innovative digital work. The conference was a whole lot of fun, and if you’re interested in some of those conversations, I recommend &lt;a href=&quot;http://thenewrigor.org&quot;&gt;checking out the conference’s website&lt;/a&gt;, which has documentation and notes out the wazoo. I don’t want to talk about evaluating digital projects, though—I want to talk about making silly sproingy toys in Javascript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;sproingcanvas&quot; class=&quot;canvas&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a force-directed graph (named because it simulates physical forces, &lt;em&gt;e.g.&lt;/em&gt; sproinginess) represented all of the tweets sent out during &lt;em&gt;The New Rigor&lt;/em&gt;, mostly between 1 PM and 1:45 PM on May 2nd, 2015. During the conference, we split participants up into color groups that more or less tracked their role in academia: red for undergraduates, orange for staff members, blue for graduate students, green for tenure-track faculty, and purple for tenured faculty. The colors of each of the nodes (those circles representing tweets) matches the tweeter’s color group. Hovering over the node displays the tweeter’s username, real name (well, their name that they go by on Twitter!) and the text of their tweet. Double-clicking any node highlights it and all nodes connected to it, and of course, you can drag the whole graph around like colorful Slinky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made this visualization using &lt;a href=&quot;http://d3js.org&quot;&gt;D3.js&lt;/a&gt;, a Javascript library for making (and I paraphrase from the explanations of D3 littered across the World Wide Web) flexible data-driven documents. Charts, graphs, &lt;a href=&quot;http://koalastothemax.com&quot;&gt;pixel toys that reveal koalas&lt;/a&gt;: if it’s made of data and visuals, D3’s got your back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/newrigor-1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;To the max!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, as fun as sproingy data is, it doesn’t really tell us anything interesting about the tweets, other than eyeballing the number of tweets in each color group. The ostensible value of tweets is as a record of the day’s proceedings. How could we get a better sense of what &lt;em&gt;The New Rigor&lt;/em&gt; was talking about, from a macro view?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;timelinecanvas&quot; class=&quot;canvas&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey, would you look at that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just a slice of all of the tweets, but it encapsulates the majority of all of the tweets tagged with particular color groups, which corresponds nicely to the conference’s primary breakout session. It’s interesting to see which groups tweeted the most (staff, in orange, are the runaway victors), as well as what themes emerged at different points of the conversation. The most common talking point, as I can see it, is the value of failure, and the challenge of learning how to articulate failure as a useful scholarly practice. This is something that I thought about frequently as I put together this blog post: i.e., the value of repeated (endlessly repeated) failure when trying to get embedded D3 to work in my posts!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in the full visualizations, you can check them out over on &lt;em&gt;The New Rigor’s&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://thenewrigor.org&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, and if you want to see the source code, you can find that on my GitHub under the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jeffreymoro/newrigor-viz&quot;&gt;newrigor-viz&lt;/a&gt; repo. I’m currently working on some wordclouds and tweet walls, and will write up another blog post once I get those up and running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;/public/js/d3sproing.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;/public/js/newrigortimeline.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On Amnesia</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/08/20/on-amnesia/"/>
   <updated>2015-08-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2015/08/20/on-amnesia</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This is a post that I wrote back in the fall of 2014 for &lt;a href=&quot;http://gaming.thecritical.is&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Critical Is&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. When setting up this blog, this felt like as good a post as any to port over, given that 1) I’m proud of it and 2) the issues it raises have not gotten any better in the intervening year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;amnesiaborder0&quot; class=&quot;bleed&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;when-old-technology-all-but-disappears-in-the-face-of-the-new-how-do-we-value-remembering&quot;&gt;When old technology all but disappears in the face of the new, how do we value remembering?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first few weeks of September, 2014 were a hard couple of weeks to play video games. Specifically, to play video games from any cultural position other than that of a straight, white, young, middle-class male. On some level, we know this already, and while I wish I could say that I’ve been surprised by the rampant, unmitigated vitriol, no longer “trending towards” but rather actively resorting to violent threats, against &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/morning-mix/wp/2014/08/29/gaming-vlogger-anita-sarkeesian-is-forced-from-home-after-receiving-harrowing-death-threats/&quot;&gt;Anita Sarkeesian since she posted the most recent video in her Tropes vs. Women in Video Games series&lt;/a&gt;, against &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2014/sep/01/how-to-attack-a-woman-who-works-in-video-games&quot;&gt;female developers and critics guilty of no crimes save daring to exist, let alone work in the games industry&lt;/a&gt;— but the sound has turned to noise. I remain disgusted, appalled, and enraged, but not surprised: we all know too well by now the history of a particular subset of gaming culture’s hostility to any perceived attacks on its “territory.” Even when these attacks are nothing more than daring to &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt;. Prominent women, LGBT, or non-white developers and critics have been quite literally forced from their homes in online attacks that, in their organization, militancy, and ideology can only be described (I wish I were being hysterical, but I am not) as terrorism: this is, horrifically, business as usual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a number of ways to read these fraught, terrifying moments, and I’m thankful that gaming journalism, journalism in general, and individual bloggers have stepped up over the past few weeks to provide numerous sane, intelligent, and necessarily excoriating takes. I’ll link to some here, and more at the bottom of this essay. The bulk of these pieces have focused on the cultural side of things: Leigh Alexander, in &lt;em&gt;Gamasutra&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gamasutra.com/view/news/224400/Gamers_dont_have_to_be_your_audience_Gamers_are_over.php&quot;&gt;writes of how the sociological classification of “gamers” is dying off&lt;/a&gt;; in &lt;em&gt;Buzzfeed&lt;/em&gt;, Joseph Bernstein &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buzzfeed.com/josephbernstein/gaming-is-leaving-gamers-behind#.meBXz3Ddd&quot;&gt;maps the synecdochic fallacy of “gamers” onto cinema&lt;/a&gt;; Ian Steadman in &lt;em&gt;The New Statesman&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newstatesman.com/future-proof/2014/08/tropes-vs-anita-sarkeesian-passing-anti-feminist-nonsense-critique&quot;&gt;eviscerates the supposed “critique” of Sarkeesian’s work from her violent detractors as “anti-feminist nonsense.”&lt;/a&gt; In essence, each essay describes the same anthropological moment: a subculture, confronted with obsolence, lashes out. It’s primal—a battle over perceived territory and relevance aided by the anonymity of social media and abetted by a long history of companies prizing or denigrating communities in the marketplace. “Real gamers are X,” went the marketing canard for well over a decade, “and never Y.” This historical relic collapses, as each of the aforementioned essays shows, in the face of today’s wide(r) variety of games and gamers. “Games,” as a monolithic cultural category encompassing only a narrow slice of experiences, fall apart; the &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty&lt;/em&gt; center cannot hold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m loath to simply this trajectory, though, or to frame it as inevitable that the stereotypical “gamers” (and we need a better name for this subculture, given that, as Bernstein shows, “gamers” is as specific and critically useful as “moviegoers”) will disappear, or assimilate peacefully. To do so not only obscures the fact htat the ongoing abuse and harrasment of subaltern voices in the games community will not simply stop over time, but requires, like any other attempt at social justice, solidarity, vigilance, and action. I’m worried, as well, about the ways that the current technological and economic superstructures of capital-VG Video Gaming as a medium actively restrict our collective abilities to maintain a kind of critical historical memory that can inform and sustain us against future injustice. We shouldn’t seek to overcome the strictures of our pasts only to turn around and erase them from our memory — and I’m concerned that the games industry itself (like any technology industry) is invested, has always been invested, on the level of hardware and code, in this kind of forgetting. Furthermore, our attempts at engaging with video games in thoughtful, critical, and reflexive ways—the kinds of ways that Sarkeesian seeks to engage with games—will continue to come up short when faced with these kinds of encoded amnesia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By “forgetting,” in this context, I want to address what I see as twinned issues: first, the idea of an archive as central to any critical apparatus; and second, the ways that the games industry actively substitutes nostalgia for historicity, and in doing so, encourages the existence of the idea of a subculture of “gamers” (which, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/HanFreakinSolo/status/507509617623302144&quot;&gt;as these tweets&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/HanFreakinSolo/status/507509685222924288&quot;&gt;from games developer Patrick Lindsey&lt;/a&gt; point out, with no small amount of invective, that “gamer” is first and foremost a corporate identity) that perpetuates, on some level, this violence. These are broad issues that I’m interested in teasing out over future blog posts, so in the spirit of concision, I’d like to explore some of the technological and material issues at play here, and see how they link up to the economic and cultural apparatuses surrounding them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;amnesiaborder1&quot; class=&quot;bleed&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;first-lets-talk-about-backwards-compatibility&quot;&gt;First, let’s talk about backwards compatibility.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The games industry, like the technology industry as a whole, thrives on the idea of planned obsolescence. Apple is its king: it strategically makes key features exclusive to each subsequent iteration of iDevice in order to encourage you to upgrade as frequently as possible. In the games industry (and here I’m restricting my view, for a moment, to consoles), obsolescence works very simply: with each new console generation (Super Nintendo to Nintendo 64; Playstation 3 to PS4), you generally have to buy a whole new crop of games, and bury your old ones in the closet. Frequently, new games will be on entirely different physical formats — Blu Ray discs instead of DVD; radically different shaped cartridges — that send the obvious message, “You can’t fit us into that new box.” It works on the level of software, too, through iterative series like &lt;em&gt;Mario Kart&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;FIFA&lt;/em&gt;. With each passing year, we usher in the new and force out the old: this, we have accepted, is the tidal churn of progress. You can &lt;em&gt;see&lt;/em&gt; this progress, as a consumer, in the physical shape and composition of the media containers themselves. To take the progression of my own childhood into account, there was something compelling about seeing the boxy edges of the Super Nintendo’s cartridges round off for the N64, before eventually moving to discs (a real sign of technological progress — the kids across the street, who were a Playstation family, had had discs for years!). The physical media educates the consumer to relate to her games as ephemeral, as soon-to-be-superceded, as imminently obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Backwards compatibility works against this churn. It’s the basic idea that the software of the past be executable by the hardware of the present. It’s the expectation that my less-powerful games that I bought last year can be played on my more-powerful console I buy next year. It makes logical sense: obviously, I can’t play new games on old hardware because of Progress, but why can’t I play old games on my new, shiny system? After all, I paid for them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unsurprisingly, the console industry isn’t a huge fan, given that planned obsolescence can make a positive impact on revenue. Moreover, given how (and Hollywood has co-opted this view in recent years) major publishers’ profits in recent years are dependent on major tent-pole releases in “evergreen” series like &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Grand Theft Auto&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;Assassin’s Creed&lt;/em&gt;, there’s a present drive to convince the consumer that she needs to purchase the newest iteration, that all of the old iterations were incomplete compared this, this newest one. For these reasons and more, backwards compatibility has been traditionally altogether absent on consoles, although it thrived on Nintendo’s handheld Gameboy and DS platforms, where the previous generation of games was always playable on the current hardware (one imagines for marketing reasons as much as Nintendo’s particular niche in the industry as a purveryor of nostalgia), though revisions of each piece of hardware eventually excised these features as well, ostensibly in the name of portability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a two-fold effect this had on me as a child, and, honestly, continues to have on me as an adult. The first is a kind of frustration coupled with resignation coupled with consumerist delight as I swipe my card every four years or so — a familiar feeling, now, to anyone who owns a smartphone. In a way, this feeling of being forced, by the hand of industry, to dispose of last year’s possessions has been normalized by Apple, Samsung, et al. — as video games have reached a broader audience, frequently through the smartphone as a platform, so too have its industry’s obsolescence strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second is an urge to collect, to store, to have a physical memory of systems past. I’ve made it a point to hold onto most of the systems and games of my childhood, for two reasons: first, because I still find the games fun to play; and second, because of a twinned feeling of nostalgia for the past and anxiety that the past will someday disappear, that the software will stop running, that the hardware will break down, and I’ll be left with the shell of a talisman, unable to summon the spirit. This is already happening to some of my games. &lt;em&gt;Pokémon&lt;/em&gt; fans of a certain age and a certain temperament will recognize the moment you put in an old cartridge, say, from 1998 or so, and found that the game would run fine, but would not save, because the small battery burrowed away in each cartridge had finally run out. You can replace that battery, sure, with solder and gumption, but it’s a concrete object lesson in the impermanence and entropy of all physical systems. How long until the battery runs out again? How long will you keep replacing it? When do you decide your memory is enough?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One can understand, on some level, the territoriality this inspires in fans of this, or perhaps any computational media. It evokes a fascination with a very specific kind of past — imagined to be your own past — and fetishizes it as imminently on the verge of erasure. Because, in the context of the market, it is. Games publishers have begun to realize this in recent years, and have increasingly made very specific games from the past available for contemporary consumers, generally in the form of an HD re-release (akin to a remaster, and always changing some key pieces of the game, whether upgrading graphics or changing key gameplay) or, as Nintendo and Sony have done with the Virtual Console and Playstation Plus, respectively, developing digital store-fronts through which consumers can (re)purchase old games to play in emulation on their current systems. (No word, though, on whether or not these games will be portable to future systems, or how many times consumers will have to re-purchase what is in essence their own, personal archive.) In independent games development, “retro” has become an aesthetic, code for punishingly difficult platformers with blocky, 8-bit graphics. It’s the memory of a very particular demographic, useful to those selling the games, but not particularly useful to those playing them, or writing about them, or even making them. All it does is allow the monolithic corporations of the games industry — not even the smaller developers on the ground, many of whom are doing genuinely interesting, innovative work — to control the terms of their own histories, to map the terrain of our memories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;amnesiaborder2&quot; class=&quot;bleed&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-obvious-answer-might-be-developing-robust-games-archives&quot;&gt;The obvious answer might be developing robust games archives.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not a revolutionary claim by any means, and many spaces within and outside academia, like the &lt;a href=&quot;http://gamecenter.nyu.edu&quot;&gt;NYU Game Center&lt;/a&gt;, the MoMA’s new &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.moma.org/explore/inside_out/2013/06/28/video-games-seven-more-building-blocks-in-momas-collection&quot;&gt;video games collection&lt;/a&gt;, UC-Boulder’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://mediaarchaeologylab.com&quot;&gt;Media Archaeology Lab&lt;/a&gt;, the Internet Archive’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/consolelivingroom&quot;&gt;Console Living Room&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jsmess/jsmess&quot;&gt;JSMESS emulator&lt;/a&gt; are taking incredible steps towards a future of critical gaming. The archive is an attractive solution, particularly for games and technology more generally, given the complex technical and logistical requirements of born-digital media preservation. It’s the uphill battle of digital media, in that there’s always more and more &lt;em&gt;stuff&lt;/em&gt;, and it all requires exacting, particular systems to get it right, whether its figuring out the logistics of a collection of physical hardware and media, or working out the precise systems that go into &lt;a href=&quot;http://arstechnica.com/gaming/2011/08/accuracy-takes-power-one-mans-3ghz-quest-to-build-a-perfect-snes-emulator/&quot;&gt;emulating software&lt;/a&gt;. None of what I’ve pointed out above begins to grapple with the large community of indie developers working on platforms like Twine, or what to do with all of the games from the 2000s that were written in soon-to-be-obsolete Flash. (Although, for thoughts on that issue, you might want to check out Zach Whalen’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zachwhalen.net/posts/lexia-to-perplexia-2000-2013/&quot;&gt;talk from MLA 2013&lt;/a&gt; on the seminal, though now un-executable, piece of electronic literature, Talan Memmott’s Lexia to Perplexia.) The attractiveness of “build archives” as a solution is that it makes all of these questions, on some level, somebody’s else’s problem — someone with The Skills, The Knowledge, and, most importantly, The Time. We need to reconfigure (or at least, take a fresh look at) our relationship to electronic media, to the open-source and proprietary systems we use to create and execute that media, and to our relationship with the larger economic interests that, at practically every level, manage and condition these relationships. I’m not calling for the End Of All Games Corporations. I might be calling for the End Of Games Corporations As Their Own Historians, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s something insidious about asking (allowing!) games publishers to be their own archivists. Doing so denies players and critics access to a more-complete picture of gaming history. Like so many of the larger questions of sexism in the technology industry (think of Ubisoft’s claim that it couldn’t find resources to program and design a female protagonist in the upcoming &lt;em&gt;Assassin’s Creed: Unity&lt;/em&gt; because of budgetary limitations), it cloaks a sociological problem as an engineering problem, as if framing it all in questions of numbers and code would absolve publishers of a humanistic, moral, and cultural reckoning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post’s title is partially misleading. There is nothing, arguably, about the medium of gaming (understood as an abstraction) that predestines historical amnesia. We don’t have to have computing systems, on some level, predicated on erasing the past with each forward step — and turning on that erasure more and more frequently with each passing year. Maybe that would slow down progress, or make innovation more difficult. I don’t pretend to have the breadth of technological knowledge and experience necessary to determine that. But looking at the past few weeks (months, years, decades) of rage, violence, and injustice, I don’t know if slowing down and cultivating a better sense of the fullness of our past would be such a terrible thing.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>This is a blog post</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/08/18/this-is-a-blog-post/"/>
   <updated>2015-08-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2015/08/18/this-is-a-blog-post</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello! This my blog, and this is a blog post. Welcome: I brought snacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you want to see what a paragraph looks like on my new blog? Here you go:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor incididunt ut labore et dolore magna aliqua. Ut enim ad minim veniam, quis nostrud exercitation ullamco laboris nisi ut aliquip ex ea commodo consequat. Duis aute irure dolor in reprehenderit in voluptate velit esse cillum dolore eu fugiat nulla pariatur. Excepteur sint occaecat cupidatat non proident, sunt in culpa qui officia deserunt mollit anim id est laborum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can put that paragraph in block quotes, too:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor incididunt ut labore et dolore magna aliqua. Ut enim ad minim veniam, quis nostrud exercitation ullamco laboris nisi ut aliquip ex ea commodo consequat. Duis aute irure dolor in reprehenderit in voluptate velit esse cillum dolore eu fugiat nulla pariatur. Excepteur sint occaecat cupidatat non proident, sunt in culpa qui officia deserunt mollit anim id est laborum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also figured out how to include sweet, sweet code:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;table style=&quot;border-spacing: 0&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter gl&quot; style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8
9
10
11
12
13
14
15
16
17
18&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;tabsWrapper clear&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;id=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;t0&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;ul&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;tabs&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;#t1&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;EDUCATION&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;#t2&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;EMPLOYMENT HISTORY&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;#t3&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;AWARDS + FELLOWSHIPS&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;#t4&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;SCHOLARY + CREATIVE PROJECTS&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;#t5&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;PUBLIC PRESENTATIONS&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;#t6&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;COURSES + WORKSHOPS&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;#t7&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;SKILLS&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t anticipate using that one that much, although it does make me feel &lt;em&gt;super&lt;/em&gt; cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay: that’s it for now! Look at me, blogging. I never thought the day would come. Did you read down all the way to here expecting to learn something? Good: I wouldn’t want you to think that at all.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
